<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Chris Titus Tech</title>
    <link>/new/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Chris Titus Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 16:15:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/new/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CTT Newsletter – October 2019</title>
      <link>/ctt-newsletter-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ctt-newsletter-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>This is the first newsletter that I am sending out and is meant as a quick monthly recap of all the content that is provided. I don’t want to blow up your inbox with junk, but want to provide you extra value by linking tutorial guides and video playlists that may interest you. If you like this format and are not yet signed up, you can sign up at https://community.christitus.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Kernel in Linux</title>
      <link>/custom-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/custom-kernel/</guid>
      <description>This Guide walks your through how to install a custom kernel on Linux. I will go over performing this in a Debian-based system and an Arch-based system. Please note that the arch based system requires you to build the kernel yourself and will take much longer.
Custom kernels in Linux are based on the Zen project and have some workstation/desktop optimizations. They are NOT meant for server installations. These are meant for those using Linux Desktop and utilizing it for Gaming, Production, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux File System | Directory Structure</title>
      <link>/linux-file-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linux-file-system/</guid>
      <description>This article details the Linux File System and it’s directory structure.
Linux File System – Root  / -This is the root directory which should contain only the directories needed at the top level of the file structure /bin – This is where the executable files are located. These files are available to all users, but do not add programs manually here /dev – These are devices in your system – Not Mounted!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup a VPN Server and Clients Using OpenVPN</title>
      <link>/openvpn-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 04:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/openvpn-server/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I go over how to setup a VPN Server and clients using OpenVPN. this will cover the setup process of the remote machine and then connecting to it via both Linux and Windows client machines.
OpenVPN Server Setup This is the Installation script I use to setup a secure OpenVPN Server
https://github.com/angristan/openvpn-install
Run the following script as root or add sudo to the install.sh script
curl -O https://raw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate SSH Guide</title>
      <link>/ssh-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 21:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ssh-guide/</guid>
      <description>This is an SSH guide to help you set up, configure, connect, and transfer files using SSH.
Setup SSH Install SSH on your system Debian-Based sudo apt install openssh-server -y
CentOS/Fedora sudo yum -y install openssh-server
Arch sudo pacman -S openssh
Run SSH server on startup sudo systemctl start ssh&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; sudo systemctl enable ssh
**Note: sshd instead of ssh for arch
Configure SSH Make sure ufw isn’t blocking ssh and enable it for passthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to the Latest Version of GIMP</title>
      <link>/latest-version-of-gimp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/latest-version-of-gimp/</guid>
      <description>Here are instructions on how to Update to the latest version of GIMP. This is vital to make sure you get the newest and best features for GIMP. The old versions of gimp that come bundled with Ubuntu 18 and prior aren’t nearly as good as Gimp 2.10+.
Start by launching terminal and adding the GIMP repository
Verify the apt updates and if it doesn’t run the following command
Now simply install GIMP and it will automatically update to the latest version of GIMP from now on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigDaddyLinux Interview</title>
      <link>/bigdaddylinux-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 23:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bigdaddylinux-interview/</guid>
      <description>I had a great time chatting with Rocco from BDL and loved his interview style. I didn’t realize we talked for an hour and half, but had an absolute blast and will definitely jump in on some more of his live streams. Here is the interview:If you get a chance and want to see the other people he has interviewed, here is his YouTube channel and website:
 https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCtZRKfyvx7GUEi-Lr7f4Nxg https://www.bigdaddylinux.com  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grub Rescue | Repairing your Bootloader</title>
      <link>/grub-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 22:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/grub-rescue/</guid>
      <description>Lets go over Grub Rescue and repairing your bootloader. This is a very misunderstood topic and by learn basic syntax you will be able to repair your GRUB very easily. Here are 4 methods of doing a GRUB Rescue.
Repairing from a GRUB &amp;gt; Prompt Find your Hard drive
ls
Output Example: (hd0) (hd0,msdos2) (hd0,msdos1)
List Root partition on each drive til you find your Install
ls (hd0,msdos2)/
Check for the directory listing, if nothing, move to next</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress on Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>/wordpress-google-cloud-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/wordpress-google-cloud-platform/</guid>
      <description>I am going over hosting WordPress on Google Cloud Platform in this article. This is a step by step guide on how to set up and host a WordPress website using a fresh installation.
Step 1: Fresh VM console.cloud.google.com(Note: Be sure and install gcloud https://cloud.google.com/sdk/docs/downloads-apt-get&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;)
Setup Project and VM (micro)
sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt upgrade
Step 2: Install Swap $ sudo fallocate -l 1G /swapfile&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;$ sudo dd if=/dev/zero of=/swapfile bs=1024 count=1048576&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;$ sudo chmod 600 /swapfile&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;$ sudo mkswap /swapfile&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;$ sudo swapon /swapfile&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;$ sudo nano /etc/fstab&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;-- /swapfile swap swap defaults 0 0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aptitude Explained</title>
      <link>/aptitude-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aptitude-explained/</guid>
      <description>In this articleI am going over the aptitude command and explaining all of the commands and usage that goes with its usage.
Install Aptitude Run the following command to install aptitude and task select: sudo apt install aptitude tasksel
Why Aptitude? Aptitude provides greater dependency resolution and wildcard installations. Making installing or reinstalling entire packages far easier. For instance the following command installs KDE in a simple command: aptitude install ~t^desktop$ ~t^kde-desktop$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 13 – European Union and YouTube</title>
      <link>/article-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article-13/</guid>
      <description>This is about Article 13 and Why it is actually great for YouTube as a company but will cause more censorship across the European Union.
The main debate is holding the sharing platform liable for any damages sustained. YouTube is angling to say they are protecting copyright holders due to their Content ID system and might be able to corner the marketplace.
There is a specific provision in Article 13 that I think Google will leverage and completely annihilate the competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Express on Linux | Step by Step Guide</title>
      <link>/garmin-express-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 22:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/garmin-express-linux/</guid>
      <description>This is an installation guide on how to get Garmin Express on Linux working. In this Step by Step Guide, I go over creating a new wine bottle and installing Garmin Express in it.
Linux Package Requirements:  wine-devel Note:3.19 or higher winetricks  Installation Steps First we start by creating a wineprefix and installing our prerequisites from terminal:
Note: You will be prompted during the setup for .NET installation just hit next and finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manjaro Architect Installation Guide</title>
      <link>/manjaro-architect-installation-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 19:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/manjaro-architect-installation-guide/</guid>
      <description>In this book, I go over step by step the entire Manjaro Architect installation. This guide is suitable for any knowledge level from beginner to expert. I published “The Complete Manjaro Architect Installation Guide” on Amazon so, if you are installing on your main PC you can follow along without constantly scrolling through on your phone trying to find what you are looking for. I highly recommend watching the video below, and doing a trial of Manjaro Architect in a virtual machine to familiarize yourself with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resize LVM Partition | Fedora 29 | Step by Step Guide</title>
      <link>/resize-lvm-partition-fedora-29-step-by-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 19:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resize-lvm-partition-fedora-29-step-by-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, I show you how to Resize LVM Partition in Fedora 29. I recently ran out of space and had to clone my install from a 120SSD ssd to a 240 GB SSD. I first had issues with boot timing out and causing the /dev/mapper/home, /dev/mapper/swap, and /dev/mapper/root not being found. To fix this, I simply rebooted to the rescue kernel and ran dracut --regenerate-all -f to resolve this in Single-User Mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech C920 Linux Driver | Fix Lag and Disable Auto-Focus</title>
      <link>/logitech-c920-linux-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 20:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/logitech-c920-linux-driver/</guid>
      <description>With my webcam, I was having major issues and tried looking for a Logitech C920 Linux Driver, as I have a Logitech C920 Webcam that is very laggy in Linux, but in Windows, I don’t have any issues. I found out that the autofocus and exposure were causing a ton of issues and I had no way to disable these features. After following this guide, you will be able to fix this issue if you run into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar Data Recovery Standard Review</title>
      <link>/stellar-data-recovery-standard-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 14:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stellar-data-recovery-standard-review/</guid>
      <description>This is a review of the Standard version of Stellar Data Recovery software. I go over the cost, performance, and result of the recovery.
Features  Recovers data from multiple devices Sorts devices by folder Photo, Video, and Documents restored in Standard Edition  The features are good for the standard edition, and I have nothing bad to say about what is included. I have used various other pieces of software and for this price point, I was happy with the feature set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clearing out Orphaned Shadow Copies</title>
      <link>/orphaned-shadow-copies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 15:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/orphaned-shadow-copies/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I go over how to get rid of Orphaned Shadow Copies that do not get cleared out by issuing: vssadmin shadows delete /all
Steps to clear out all orphaned shadow copies  vssadmin shadows delete /all vssadmin shadows list  verify orphaned shadow copies still exist   Use the following command to resize shadow storage, consequently, clears out any shadow copies on that drive  vssadmin Resize ShadowStorage /For=C: /On=C: /MaxSize=300MB  Note: Repeat this for each drive with orphaned shadow copies     Afterward, do a shadows list to verify the shadow copies have been cleared out  This process can take a very long time for large drives with a lot of shadow copies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Plex plugin in FreeNAS</title>
      <link>/install-plex-plugin-freenas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 19:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/install-plex-plugin-freenas/</guid>
      <description>This is an in-depth installation and configuration of the Plex plugin in FreeNAS 11.2. I detail the installation of plex on FreeNAS Jail and configuration of using a share as a Plex mount point.
Plex plugin in FreeNAS Steps  Install Plex Plugin  Under Plugins -&amp;gt; Availiable   Set Static IP  Interface em0 (or your interface name), Static IP for Plex Server, and Netmask (/24 is 255.255.255.0)   Stop Plugin Edit Plex Jail – Mount Point – Note: This is only used if you want a share to add movies to your plex from another computer  Set Source Share (/mnt/sharename/) and Set Destination (I selected the media folder in the jail directory)   Edit Plex Jail – Edit Confiuration  Check VNET and Berkeley Packet Filter Set Default IPv4 Route to your Gateway or Router (Ex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Linux for the First Time</title>
      <link>/install-linux-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 15:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/install-linux-first-time/</guid>
      <description>This video goes over installing Linux for the first time. I will break it down into 3 parts with a Video Walkthrough. Using this will make it very easy for you to install Linux for the first time.
Choosing the right version or flavor of Linux Latest Ubuntu Desktop LTS – https://www.ubuntu.com/download
RUFUS USB Creator for Windows – https://rufus.ie/en_IE.html
Installation Process  Download ISO for ubuntu Create a USB Thumb drive Install</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Change Cortana Search</title>
      <link>/change-cortana-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 15:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/change-cortana-search/</guid>
      <description>This article goes over how to change Cortana search engine to display results in chrome instead of Microsoft Edge. Afterward, the second part requires you to install a chrome extension to search in Google instead of Bing. Check the links below for the source code to compile, download pre-compiled, or support the developer using Windows Store.
Video Walkthrough Links from Video  https://github.com/sylveon/SearchWithMyBrowser – GitHub Source and Compile Instructions https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9PPKNR9RK26R?ocid=badge – Windows Store Link from Developer https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should I switch to Linux from Windows?</title>
      <link>/linux-switch-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 17:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linux-switch-video/</guid>
      <description>This will be the first video in a series of Linux videos and in it, I am going over 6 reasons to switch to Linux and 1 big reason not to. Many people ask “Why should I switch to Linux from Windows?” and in the video below I break it down for you.
Why should I switch to Linux from Windows – Video Pros  It’s Free – Tons of Free software No big brother – Microsoft Telemetry reports on you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup FreeNAS 11</title>
      <link>/setup-freenas-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 16:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/setup-freenas-11/</guid>
      <description>This article goes over how to setup FreeNAS 11 and configure it. These are the basic steps so you can have a reliable network storage at your house.
Steps to setup FreeNAS 11  Download FreeNAS stable from http://www.freenas.org/download-freenas-release/ Create Thumb drive from iso and Win32DiskImager https://sourceforge.net/projects/win32diskimager/  Note: DO NOT use Rufus or Yumi as these won’t create a bootable thumb drive   Install and Follow the Prompts Set Static IP Reboot Login to Web Interface with IP from Step 4 Set up Storage Pool Assign SMB Share  Make sure allow guest access is checked   Configure SMB Share Service  Auto-Start and Enabled Configure Guest user to be root   Test!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Xen Orchestra</title>
      <link>/how-to-install-xen-orchestra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-install-xen-orchestra/</guid>
      <description>This article shows you how to install Xen Orchestra and use the interface via the web. XOA is a very powerful addition to XenServer as it brings auto-updates and making it easier to manage entire farms.
Step-by-Step Guide  Login to your XenServer via PuTTy OR through XenCenter console Type bash -c &amp;quot;$(curl -s http://xoa.io/deploy)&amp;quot;  Enter a new IP where you will access XOA from web Wait for this to finish you will see XOA VM popup Note: This may take a couple hours if XOA servers are downloading slow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create iSCSI SR in XenServer</title>
      <link>/create-iscsi-sr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 16:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/create-iscsi-sr/</guid>
      <description>This guide goes over how to Create iSCSI SR on Xen to connect to an iSCSI target. Here is the step-by-step and a video walkthrough, which includes setting up iSCSI in FreeNAS.
Requirements  Multiple XenServers (2+) in a Pool iSCSI target (Check out FreeNAS in the video below for setting one up) At LEAST a gigabit environment   Step-by-Step Guide to Create iSCSI SR  Open and Connect to XenCenter / XCP-ng Center Select Pool and Click New Storage Make sure iSCSI is selected Name Storage Select either provisioning methods Enter IP Address / Authentication (if needed) / Click Scan Target Host Pick IQN / LUN from your storage device  Note: When Selecting IQN_, make sure you select your SAN if you are using a dedicated network_   Finish  Video Walkthrough In the end, we now have a centralized storage system that all our hosts can put their VMs on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Windows Firewall Properly</title>
      <link>/disable-windows-firewall-properly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 17:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/disable-windows-firewall-properly/</guid>
      <description>This walkthrough goes over how to Disable Windows Firewall while not affecting other programs that rely on this service. It’s important that you **DO NOT **disable the service, due to the fact it can cause issues with Microsoft Office and other products.
 Steps to bypass firewall  Launch Windows Defender Firewall with Advanced Security (Start -&amp;gt; Run -&amp;gt; wf.msc) Click Inbound Rules Select “New Rule” Custom rule All Programs Leave Any and All Ports Any IP Address for both Allow the connection Check Domain, Private, and Public Name “Allow All”  Video Guide Finishing Up By doing this you allow all traffic inbound to this computer, consequently, all outbound traffic is already allowed by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SATA vs SAS vs NVMe Performance Breakdown</title>
      <link>/sata-vs-sas-vs-nvme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sata-vs-sas-vs-nvme/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick breakdown of the differences between SATA vs SAS vs NVMe. After looking at the performance below, you will be able to decide which one best suits your needs.
 SATA (Serial Advanced Technology Advancement)  Most common Least reliable Slow  5400 – 7200 RPM Hard Drives Half duplex (Can’t read and write simultaneously) 6 GB/s connection   Cheap (1 TB SSD $150)   SAS (Serial Attached Storage)  Commonplace in data centers Very reliable  Error checking is built-in   Fast  15k RPM Hard Drives Full Duplex (Simultaneous read and write) 12 GB/s connection   Expensive (800 GB SSD $600) – Pretty much enterprise only   NVMe (Non-Volatile Memory Express)  Common in new PC builds, common in data center SANs for cache on tiered storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and Configuring Exchange 2019</title>
      <link>/configuring-exchange-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 15:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/configuring-exchange-2019/</guid>
      <description>This article goes over what it takes for installing and configuring exchange 2019. This step-by-step guide shows you the requirements, installation steps, and basic configuration.
Requirements  Microsoft recommends 128 GB of memory. If in a medium size environment (100-1000 users) 32-64 GB will be sufficient. Microsoft Windows Server 2012 R2/2016/2019 Co-Existence with Exchange 2013/2016 that are up-to-date 30 GB of free disk space, however, you should have plenty of TBs of storage available for the mailbox stores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XenServer cannot connect in XenCenter or XCP-ng Center</title>
      <link>/xenserver-cannot-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/xenserver-cannot-connect/</guid>
      <description>Having problems and your XenServer cannot connect to XenCenter? Did you have high availability enabled? If you answered yes to both these questions here is how you get your XenServer back online and functioning properly.

Step-by-Step Guide  PuTTy into the XenServer Pool Master run the following commands:  xe pool-ha-disable_Note: If this fails try ha-disable force below_
xe host-emergency-ha-disable force=true&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; xe pool-emergency-transition-to-master --force
Note: This will force the pool and slaves to reinitialize with the pool master</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and Configuring Windows Server 2016 Core</title>
      <link>/configuring-windows-server-2016-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/configuring-windows-server-2016-core/</guid>
      <description>This guide walks you through how to installing and configuring windows server 2016 core, afterward you will easily be able to add one to your environment with very little resources. Start off by using the video guide over the installation process. Once done, check the bullets below to help walk you through doing it in your infrastructure.
Remote Server Administration Tools for Windows 10 https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=45520
 Steps to configuring windows server 2016 core  Run sconfig Configure Static IP Set Computer Name Join to Domain Set Windows Update Settings to Download ONLY Download and Install all Updates Enable Remote Desktop and Remote Management Change Telemetry to Security Activate Windows Reboot  Connecting Remotely to Server 2016 Core Finally, we can now go back to our workstation and start utilizing and configuring windows server 2016 core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Apache Memory Usage using mpm prefork</title>
      <link>/apache-mpm-prefork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 17:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/apache-mpm-prefork/</guid>
      <description>This guide goes over optimizing apache memory usage by configuring mpm prefork module to the best values for your server. Afterword, you should notice substantial increases in performance especially if you are using free micro instances from Google Cloud or AWS.
Commands used:  Check Apache Memory usage   ps -ylC apache2 --sort:rss | awk &#39;{sum+=$8; ++n} END {print &amp;quot;Tot=&amp;quot;sum&amp;quot;(&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;)&amp;quot;;print &amp;quot;Avg=&amp;quot;sum&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;=&amp;quot;sum/n/1024&amp;quot;MB&amp;quot;}&#39;
Note: My result was between 68-71 MB with stock modules loaded, however, your results will vary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide: Using EOS Ledger App with Scatter Wallet</title>
      <link>/eos-ledger-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 18:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eos-ledger-app/</guid>
      <description>This video goes over using EOS Ledger App with Scatter Wallet. Within it shows how to add the EOS app to the ledger, generate ledger public key, create an account, and do transactions on the EOS blockchain using your ledger.
Considerations  Use a backup ledger in a secure location with the same seed words if you are storing a substantial amount of EOS. Ledger does not provide a private key and there is no tool to create a private key from your seed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect htaccess for WordPress</title>
      <link>/perfect-htaccess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perfect-htaccess/</guid>
      <description>This walks you through what your htaccess should look like in a WordPress Installation. I am a minimalist and believe you shouldn’t be using a ton of plugins that slow down your install when most of what you are looking to accomplish can be achieved with this file. Therefore, this htaccess will contain bad bot blocker, security optimizations, force https, and a variety of other optimizations. This will save you from installing about 5-10 plugins that would slow down your website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Complete Beginners Guide to Getting Started on the EOS Blockchain</title>
      <link>/the-complete-beginners-guide-to-getting-started-on-the-eos-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 19:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-complete-beginners-guide-to-getting-started-on-the-eos-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>This Guide shows you everything you need that will get started on the EOS blockchain. Creating Keys, wallet, account, and using dApps are all in this guide. The following videos will get you running EOS decentralized Apps.
Watch all EOS Videos from YouTube via Playlist here: Instructional EOS Videos for beginnersFirst Video Install a Linux terminal in Windows 10 afterward we will be able to build EOS tools in here. This is important to do as you can’t compile EOS natively in windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snipping Tool Removed by Microsoft in October 2018 Update 1809</title>
      <link>/snipping-tool-removed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 19:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/snipping-tool-removed/</guid>
      <description>The Snipping Tool is being removed by Microsoft in October 2018 Update 1809 and I am not happy! This tool is one of the best tools Microsoft has ever created, so why? Well, they want you to use the Snip and Sketch App from the Microsoft Store. Spoiler: It sucks.
Greenshot the best Snipping Tool Replacement So what should you use? Greenshot. Its freeware and it just works. Not bulky with a toolbar, but adds a tray icon, which you don’t have to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Stake EOS?</title>
      <link>/stake-eos-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 15:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stake-eos-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>This video goes over how to stake EOS for CPU, RAM, and bandwidth. It shows real-world examples of staking and unstaking EOS when utilizing the EOS dApps.
Staking Basics You can stake and unstake from many dApps, but my preferred method is using the EOS Toolkit and finalizing my amounts in there. Personally, I recommend 8 KB for RAM, 15 EOS for CPU, and .1 EOS for Net as this will give you the ability to play and use pretty much any decentralized app out right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you stay in Crypto? Is it Over or Just Beginning?</title>
      <link>/stay-crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 14:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stay-crypto/</guid>
      <description>This video is out there for anyone thinking about staying in crypto or getting into it. I give my introduction to cryptocurrency and a background about me and my experiences.
View All Videos / Content / Guides / Solutions @ https://www.christitus.com
About me 0:00-15+ years in the IT Field
-3 years of Computer Science
-Researched many crypto projects
-Early Bitcoin miner when you could mine on GPU
-Early Ethereum miner and entered @ $17</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SciDex ICO Review</title>
      <link>/scidex-ico-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scidex-ico-review/</guid>
      <description>This video goes over all the aspects of the SciDex ICO and grades it based on criteria that have made ICOs successful in the past.
Official Links Official Site/
Protocol Whitepaper
MarketSpace Whitepaper
4 Criteria for ICO Review   Real World Application
  Funding
  Tangible Progress
  Misc. Concerns
  Conclusion From the look of everything, I’m betting it will be another ICO Scam. There is a possibility I am just missing the entire point of this ICO, but everything I have seen just screams that this is a project going nowhere fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using IOMeter to determine hard drive performance</title>
      <link>/using-iometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 16:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/using-iometer/</guid>
      <description>Using IOMeter will give you a great benchmark on any hard drives and network drives you have. I use this quite often as you can see the effects of new hardware, introducing Link-Aggregation, or troubleshooting drives to determine if they are losing performance.
Steps to Follow  Download IOMeter from the Official Site and run setup  
All Programs -&amp;gt; Iometer -&amp;gt; Iometer  3a) Under ‘Topology’ tab, select the local machine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issuing SSL Certs using Let’s Encrypt in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/issuing-ssl-certs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/issuing-ssl-certs/</guid>
      <description>This Video goes over Issuing SSL Certs using Let’s Encrypt in Ubuntu 16.04. The basic steps outlined in the video are adding the repository, installing certbot, issuing a certificate, and enabling SSL.
Links Let’s Encrypt @ https://letsencrypt.org/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
Certbot @ https://certbot.eff.org/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
Command List for Issuing SSL Certs sudo apt-get update&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo apt-get install software-properties-common -y&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo add-apt-repository ppa:certbot/certbot&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo apt-get update&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo apt-get install python-certbot-apache -y&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo certbot --apache</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome missing www and how to fix it</title>
      <link>/google-chrome-update-69-address-bar-and-how-to-fix-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 20:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/google-chrome-update-69-address-bar-and-how-to-fix-it/</guid>
      <description>Chrome started rolling out update 69 at the beginning of this month (September 2018) causing a missing www in the address bar. There are two things this update did that you need to be aware of.
Google Chrome Update 69 Changes  Show trivial sub-domains (missing www in the address bar)  Fix: Type this in your address bar: chrome://flags/#omnibox-ui-hide-steady-state-url-scheme-and-subdomains Set to DISABLED   Chrome now defaults to SSL / HTTPS for all websites  So I didn’t realize this happened and launched a new ubuntu web server to find it unreachable with apache installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOS Account Creation and using Accounts on the blockchain</title>
      <link>/eos-account-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 20:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eos-account-creation/</guid>
      <description>I posted an article about EOS Titled “Why EOS is destined to fail?“. Shortly after, I received a couple responses from folks that said the chain is down or not working or just simply too hard to use. It made me scratch my head and after a couple minutes searching I really didn’t find too many articles outlining how EOS works, EOS Account creation, or how an average person can use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Linux Subsystem for Windows 10</title>
      <link>/installing-linux-subsystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 19:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installing-linux-subsystem/</guid>
      <description>The following video goes over installing Linux Subsystem on Windows 10. Most notably it allows you to run Linux terminal commands in Windows 10 without having a virtual machine or dual boot into a Linux operating system. &amp;lt;iframe style=&amp;quot;display: block; margin: 0px auto;&amp;rdquo; id=&amp;rdquo;_ytid_78463&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;1200&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;quot;675&amp;rdquo; data-origwidth=&amp;quot;1200&amp;rdquo; data-origheight=&amp;quot;675&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RriP3LmuKNA?enablejsapi=1&amp;amp;autoplay=0&amp;amp;cc_load_policy=0&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=3&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;modestbranding=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;playsinline=0&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;theme=dark&amp;amp;color=red&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;rdquo;__youtube_prefs\__&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;YouTube player&amp;rdquo; allow=&amp;quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&amp;rdquo; allowfullscreen data-no-lazy=&amp;quot;1&amp;rdquo; data-skipgform_ajax_framebjll=&amp;quot;&amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;Enable Linux Subsystem Feature cd ~ Enable-WindowsOptionalFeature -Online -FeatureName Microsoft-Windows-Subsystem-Linux Note: Perform in PowerShell</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>/intro-google-cloud-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 13:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intro-google-cloud-platform/</guid>
      <description>This is an Introduction to Google Cloud Platform and goes over creating your first project and virtual machine. This walkthrough is for beginners that are just getting started with Google Cloud.
Download GCloud SDK Allows gcloud commands from command prompt
https://cloud.google.com/appengine/docs/standard/python/download
Next Steps Now that we know how to use Google Cloud Platform, go out and build up your first system. I highly recommend starting with an Ubuntu server, since they have the best community support for starters, and install a web server to host a website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup an always on VPN in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/setup-always-on-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 14:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/setup-always-on-vpn/</guid>
      <description>This is a guide on how to set up an always on VPN in Ubuntu, and basic troubleshooting of VPNs in ubuntu server. I used Private Internet Access as an example VPN connection.
Use my affiliate link to get a Private Internet Access VPN: http://www.privateinternetaccess.com/pages/buy-vpn/christitus. This is a must-have for a dedicated Linux box specifically for privacy concerns.
Setup VPN in Ubuntu – No Commentary Setup VPN in Ubuntu – With Commentary VPN setup commands: sudo su&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; apt-get install openvpn -y&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; cd /etc/openvpn&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; wget https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XCP-ng / XenServer – Your First Virtual Machine Installation</title>
      <link>/xenserver-xcp-ng-first-vm-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 18:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/xenserver-xcp-ng-first-vm-install/</guid>
      <description>This video goes through setting up a Virtual Machine in XenServer / XCP-ng in a lab environment. If you want to experiment with in detail with XenServer, I highly recommend you download XCP-ng from their official website. This is a community-powered version of XenServer with ALL FEATURES ENABLED. XenServer from Citrix has recently started going away from its open-source roots and as a result, has begun locking features behind a paywall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debloat Windows 10</title>
      <link>/debloat-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 17:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/debloat-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>Right Click Windows Button -&amp;gt;Select Powershell Prompt (Admin) OR Select Command Prompt (Admin)  Note: If you don’t have PowerShell and only command prompt open command prompt (admin) and type “powershell“   Change Execution policy to allow a debloat script to run in Powershell Set-ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted Run the script from the following Github Repository. The person running this GitHub has been updating this script for a while and is a godsend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Introduction</title>
      <link>/virtualization-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 21:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtualization-introduction/</guid>
      <description>This is a virtualization introduction and when you should be using it. In the follow-up videos, I will go into using the hypervisor, creating VMs and maintenance.
Now that you understand what it is and if you want to start getting your feet wet, please check out my other video to start installing your hypervisor and launching your first virtual machine here. I highly recommend starting out with VMware as it used the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove Asterisk from Linux server (ubuntu/centos/debian/rhel)</title>
      <link>/remove-asterisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 15:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/remove-asterisk/</guid>
      <description>The following removal instructions go over how to completely remove Asterisk from your Linux Instance.
REMOVE AND REINSTALL INSTRUCTIONS Here is how to remove Asterisk from a Linux server and reinstall from source.
Pre-requirements: Download source, configure, make menuselect_, and make. All done with root (sudo su) Example:_
sudo su&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; ###ENTER ROOT PASSWORD###&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; mkdir ~/build&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; cd ~/build&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; wget https://downloads.asterisk.org/pub/telephony/asterisk/asterisk-14-current.tar.gz&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; tar -xvf asterisk-14-current.tar.gz&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; cd asterisk-14&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repair Windows Boot Partition | Includes files and partitioning</title>
      <link>/repair-windows-boot-partition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 17:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/repair-windows-boot-partition/</guid>
      <description>This walkthrough shows you how to repair windows boot partition and boot from an existing windows installation without reinstalling windows.
Recently I had an old server with a FAT32 system reserved partition and a bunch of extra partitions. I have already moved all the data off the server and it was ready for decommissioning. Before, I did this I wanted to go ahead and remove all these old partitions and just leave the C: Drive with the Windows installation then rebuild the System Reserved partition as NTFS as an exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commiting Changes to Docker images and containers</title>
      <link>/commiting-docker-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 19:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/commiting-docker-images/</guid>
      <description>This is a walkthrough of how to commit changes to docker images and containers. You need to do this if you make configuration changes to any docker images. By committing changes to the docker images you can backup and clone them.
Docker is a very powerful tool you can use to isolate applications, therefore, you won’t have them on a single server. However, some docker images don’t save changes to their container when a restart happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Unifi Access Point to another Unifi Controller</title>
      <link>/moving-unifi-access-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 15:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/moving-unifi-access-point/</guid>
      <description>This walkthrough goes over moving Unifi access point to another Unifi controller. To remove APs from a Unifi Controller you need to reset the APs and then either discover them or manually SSH set-inform the devices.
First Reset the AP  -Use Terminal or SSH (Either in existing Controller -&amp;gt; Manage Device -&amp;gt; Open Terminal or Putty)
  -Type: syswrapper.sh restore-default
OR
Reset the Unifi AP by the old paperclip method if you can’t putty or use existing controller</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to remotely access Window Server 2016 Core in PowerShell </title>
      <link>/windows-server-2016-core-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 20:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-server-2016-core-remote/</guid>
      <description>This walkthrough shows you how to remotely access Window Server 2016 Core in PowerShell. Windows Server 2016 Core is a great minimal install of windows server but doesn’t come with any desktop experience. This means we will be doing everything via command prompt or PowerShell for the initial setup. The great thing is you use Powershell and RSAT from a Windows 10 machine and working on the server is a snap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing file permissions using PowerShell</title>
      <link>/changing-file-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 15:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/changing-file-permissions/</guid>
      <description>Use the following script for changing file permissions using PowerShell. I use this script when command line takeown and icacls fail. Obviously, run from an elevated PowerShell prompt or by typing ‘powershell’ from elevated cmd.
The Script Change $folder to the base directory you want for changing permissions.
Please note, you can use network UNC paths for this or a simple C:.
$folder = &amp;quot;\\homeserver\users\&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; $users = get-childitem $folder&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Foreach ($user in $users) {&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; $acl = Get-Acl $user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOS Dallas Presentation</title>
      <link>/eos-dallas-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 03:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eos-dallas-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Here is a recent presentation I gave at EOS Dallas. This was a brief overview of EOS Blockchain and some potential pitfalls in March of 2018
www.christitus.com/eosdallas
September 2018 Update:
Pros  ERC20 Token conversion was successful Brock Pierce was removed from his advisory role at Block.One (TLDR; He was accused of assaulting minors in his employment back in 2000 at Digital Entertainment Network.) Slow Development is no longer an issue because they have pushed out 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell Script monitors Mining Pool Hub earnings</title>
      <link>/powershell-script-to-monitor-mining-pool-hub-earnings-market-value-and-pool-exposure-for-cryptocurrencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 23:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/powershell-script-to-monitor-mining-pool-hub-earnings-market-value-and-pool-exposure-for-cryptocurrencies/</guid>
      <description>This Powershell Script monitors Mining Pool Hub earnings with market values to make a unique dashboard. Mining Pool Hub is one of the best out there with the auto exchange feature and frequent payouts. On the other hand, the website itself is very cumbersome and not user-friendly with infrequent updates. Consequently, use the following script for viewing outside of the browser, however, if you want a browser-based monitor I recommend miningpoolhubstats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python script to print out specific results from an API JSON call</title>
      <link>/api-json-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 22:03:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/api-json-call/</guid>
      <description>The following is a Python script to print out specific results from an API JSON call from a website. This basic syntax will allow you to create a value to use.
import json, urllib2 # Import libraries we will be using&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; url = urllib2.urlopen(&#39;http://baseurl.com:port/api.json&#39;) # Pull webpage into a variable&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; result = json.load(url) # Format the URL for JSON&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; allhash = result[&#39;hashrate&#39;][&#39;total&#39;] # Pull a specific array of values&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; checkhash= allhash[0] # Specify a single value in the array</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Databases Offline and/or Dropping through SQL Query</title>
      <link>/taking-databases-offline-sql-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/taking-databases-offline-sql-query/</guid>
      <description>The following SQL query is for taking databases offline, drop the offline databases, or bring them all back online. This affects every database in your SQL instance, so be very careful when using these. The following three queries will save you a considerable amount of time if repurposing an instance.
Taking databases offline and then dropping them use master;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; declare @nsql nvarchar(max);&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; select @nsql=coalesce(@nsql+CHAR(13)+CHAR(10),&#39;&#39;)+&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; &#39;ALTER DATABASE [&#39;+name+&#39;] SET OFFLINE WITH NO_WAIT;&#39;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; from master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get rid of Amazon Fire Launcher without root access</title>
      <link>/amazon-fire-launcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 21:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/amazon-fire-launcher/</guid>
      <description>This How-To shows you how to get rid of Amazon Fire Launcher without root access. Amazon Fire 5.3.3 OS can’t be downgraded or rooted, and since the Fire tablet line auto-updates, this leads many folks with the horrible experience of using the Fire OS with their gimped store/subscriptions.
The process to use Google Services and Googles Store instead is a bit involved but entirely doable on the Fire Tablets without having to root it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report Nvidia-smi Temperature to Nagios</title>
      <link>/nvidia-smi-nagios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 04:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nvidia-smi-nagios/</guid>
      <description>Here is a custom script that reports the nvidia-smi temperature of the Nvidia cards in your system using NRPE. Conversely, NRPE performs much better than NCPA and my protocol of choice.
*Note: Install NRPE to your Linux box first, and create this file (gpu_temp.sh) in your /usr/lib/nagios/plugins directory for Nagios Core 4+
Nagios NRPE Query Command check_nrpe!gpu_temp.sh
This will only query the first GPU that is found via nvidia-smi CLI command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Nagios 4 Core Installation</title>
      <link>/troubleshooting-nagios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 17:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/troubleshooting-nagios/</guid>
      <description>Use the following command to verify you have all your config and command files correct when troubleshooting Nagios core installation. This will give you a readout of any configuration errors, thus giving you the ability to fix it on the fly.
/usr/local/nagios/bin/nagios -v /usr/local/nagios/etc/nagios.cfg
I’d recommend making an alias in your .bashrc so you can just type:testnag
Here is an example of the alias I use
alias testnag=&#39;/usr/local/nagios/bin/nagios -v /usr/local/nagios/etc/nagios.cfg&#39;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spooler subsystem app high CPU usage on Windows 10</title>
      <link>/spooler-subsystem-app-cpu-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 19:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/spooler-subsystem-app-cpu-usage/</guid>
      <description>Perform the following steps to solve the Spooler subsystem app high CPU usage. I recently updated a computer to Windows 10 and found that the spooler service was using a lot of resources.
The Solution  Open up command prompt as administrator and type the following  net stop spooler&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; del /Q /F /S &amp;quot;%systemroot%\System32\Spool\Printers\*.*&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; net start spooler&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Conclusion Now check task manager again and verify the Spooler subsystem app is now at 0% usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a startup program to run as administrator</title>
      <link>/run-as-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 02:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/run-as-administrator/</guid>
      <description>The following script shows you how to launch a startup program to run as administrator in Windows 10. This fixes many programs that require elevation and you don’t want to launch manually every time.
Almost every online tutorial I came across said to run it as a scheduled task. This is very cumbersome and I hate it, however using the following method is easier and saves you time.
Create a Text file in shell:startup and put the following in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to choose DNS Server by benchmarking them</title>
      <link>/benchmark-dns-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 17:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/benchmark-dns-server/</guid>
      <description>By default, your DNS Server is set to your ISP’s DNS and this SLOWS down your internet, due to the fact, they are poorly managed and have horrid performance. This shows you how to choose the fastest DNS Server, but results will vary depending on the location. Running this benchmark will tell you which ones are the best to use.
Finding the Fastest Go to https://www.grc.com/dns/benchmark.htm and download the benchmark tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud migration hosting in Google, Amazon, or Microsoft</title>
      <link>/cloud-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 21:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud-migration/</guid>
      <description>Moving to the Cloud The following article outlines what it takes for a cloud migration to Google Cloud Compute, Amazon Web Services, or Microsoft Azure means. Most businesses want to move to the “cloud” but have no idea what that means. If you’re a small business you typically have a couple computers scattered around with one storage device. If you’re a medium or large business you probably already have several servers at a location in a contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Swap file on Cloud VM (AWS, GCloud, or Azure)</title>
      <link>/create-swap-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 21:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/create-swap-file/</guid>
      <description>Use the commands below to create swap file on a micro instance with a Linux operating system. This creates a 2GB Swap file to help alleviate low system ram. Consequently, this is great for those using micro instances in the cloud that have under 1 GB of memory.
Commands Run the following from your SSH window
sudo fallocate -l 2G /swapfile&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo chmod 600 /swapfile&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo mkswap /swapfile&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo swapon /swapfile&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo swapon -s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating LDAP Credentials for Netscaler VPX 1000</title>
      <link>/update-netscaler-vpx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 15:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/update-netscaler-vpx/</guid>
      <description>This article shows you how to update LDAP credentials on the Netscaler VPX 1000. It goes over logging in, editing virtual server, and applying settings.
Login to the NetScaler Device Default User: nsroot Pass: nsroot (or password you changed it to)
Go to Netscaler gateway virtual server controlling your logins 
Click on LDAP Policy and select Edit Server 
Update the credentials under connection settings, and also test the new settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclude shared mailboxes from Dynamic Distribution Group</title>
      <link>/exclude-shared-mailboxes-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 20:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exclude-shared-mailboxes-exchange/</guid>
      <description>This shows you how to exclude shared mailboxes from a Dynamic Distribution Group in Exchange Online. We will be using Powershell to make sure your shared mailboxes don’t get spam in them.
 Commands Connect to O365 in PS: $UserCredential = Get-Credential&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; $Session = New-PSSession -ConfigurationName Microsoft.Exchange -ConnectionUri https://outlook.office365.com/powershell-liveid/ -Credential $UserCredential -Authentication Basic -AllowRedirection&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Import-PSSession $Session
Exclude Shared Mailboxes with this filter command: set-DynamicDistributionGroup -Name &amp;quot;all@yourcompany.com&amp;quot; -RecipientFilter {((RecipientType -eq &#39;UserMailbox&#39;) -and -not (RecipientTypeDetailsValue -eq &#39;SharedMailbox&#39;))}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force active directory sync to Office 365 with Azure ADSync</title>
      <link>/force-active-directory-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/force-active-directory-sync/</guid>
      <description>Use the following from an Elevated Powershell Prompt to force active directory sync to your O365 admin portal. You will be performing this on the server where Azure AD Sync is installed, however, when running this command you will need to wait 5 minutes before checking your portal to verify it is working. In larger environments, this can take a longer time.
Import-Module “C:\Program Files\Microsoft Azure AD Sync\Bin\ADSync\ADSync.psd1”&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Start-ADSyncSyncCycle -PolicyType Delta</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 10 IIS: C:\WINDOWS\system32\inetsrv\rewrite.dll failed to load</title>
      <link>/windows-10-iis-rewrite-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-10-iis-rewrite-error/</guid>
      <description>This article shows you what to do if you get the rewrite.dll failed to load in Windows 10 event viewer for Windows 10 IIS.
Commands Checked Event viewer when my website Showed up with
Service Unavailable 503 error
The Event Viewer Error was
The Module DLL C:\WINDOWS\system32\inetsrv\rewrite.dll failed to load
I went into Add/Remove Programs (Start -&amp;gt; Run-&amp;gt; appwiz.cpl) and simply repaired the following program
IIS Url Rewrite Module 2.0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleanup Server WinSxS Free Space on Server 2008 and Server 2012</title>
      <link>/winsxs-free-space-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 23:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/winsxs-free-space-server/</guid>
      <description>Run the following commands if you are running low on C: drive space. Generally, this is caused by windows updates and you need to clear WinSxS free space. Do this in your PowerShell prompt and you will free up a substantial amount of space.
Please Note: You have to run updates on Windows Server 2008 if you are far behind and these commands don’t exist!
MASTER CLEANUP: (Run this First)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reattach LVM after a reinstalling XenServer</title>
      <link>/reattach-lvm-xenserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 16:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reattach-lvm-xenserver/</guid>
      <description>This article describes how to reattach LVM or a local Storage repository on XenServer. The XenServer database has become corrupt or your XenServer does not see the local SR.
Instructions   Do a pvscan to get the Universally Unique Identifier (UUID) of an existing SR on a local disk. In this example uses UUID 39baf126-a535-549f-58d6-feeda55f7801:
pvscan
  Output: PV /dev/sda3 VG VG_XenStorage-39baf126-a535-549f-58d6-feeda55f7801 lvm2 [66.87 GB / 57.87 GB free]&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Total: 1 [66.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XenServer tapdisk experienced an error</title>
      <link>/xenserver-tapdisk-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 16:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/xenserver-tapdisk-error/</guid>
      <description>When re-attaching a SR on a fresh VM, I ran into this XenServer tapdisk error. I ran the following from XenServer console to eject all CD drives on that host. I was then able to start the VM with the old image.
xe vm-cd-eject --multiple
If your XenCenter hangs or becomes unresponsive, you can also reset the toolstack from console from a PuTTy session or if XenCenter console is working running the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Target account name is incorrect” Domain Controller Error</title>
      <link>/target-account-name-domain-controller-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 13:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/target-account-name-domain-controller-error/</guid>
      <description>This article explains how to fix the “Target account name is incorrect” error you are getting on your domain controllers. This usually stems from a system administrator doing a snapshot revert on the Domain Controller which messes up the KDC service and domain replication. It also can happen if you had a DC offline for a long time 30+ days.
Commands   Stop and disable the Key Distribution Center (KDC) service on the troubled domain controller</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citrix XenCenter error “Could not create SSL/TLS Secure Channel”</title>
      <link>/citrix-xencenter-error-ssl-secure-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 14:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/citrix-xencenter-error-ssl-secure-channel/</guid>
      <description>Running the following commands will fix the XenCenter Error. You are typically encountering this error because Windows 10 requires stronger encryption, consequently, this is prevalent on older XenServer installations. I encountered this on XenServer 6.0.
Commands  Putty in using SSH service xapissl stop mv /etc/xensource/xapi-ssl.pem /etc/xensource/xapi-ssl.pem.bak /opt/xensource/libexec/generate_ssl_cert &amp;quot;/etc/xensource/xapi-ssl.pem&amp;quot; &#39;10.100.0.40&#39; service xapissl start xe-toolstack-restart  Where you see 10.100.0.40 this is the IP of your XenServer that you are connecting to (not VM ips).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevent autodiscover on Exchange server after an Office 365 Migration</title>
      <link>/prevent-autodiscover-exchange-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 16:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/prevent-autodiscover-exchange-server/</guid>
      <description>This article teaches you how to prevent autodiscover from happening on Exchange Server. This is important on an Office 365 migration when you still need to keep your local exchange server from resolving.
Commands First change your local DNS
autodiscover.yourdomain.com cname autodiscover.office365.com
(Option 1)Next, you need to disable SCP site-wide. I did this performing a GPO Registry edit.
HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Microsoft\Office\x.0\Outlook\AutoDiscover&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Notex.0 in the above registry path corresponds to the Outlook version (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Full Access to all Public Folders for a user in Exchange</title>
      <link>/grant-full-access-public-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 16:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/grant-full-access-public-folders/</guid>
      <description>This post goes over how to grant full access to all public folders for a user in Microsoft Exchange. I recently was migrating all public folders from an Exchange 2010 to Office 365 Environment and didn’t have access to some of the folders. Consequently, this solution saved me a lot of time from doing it through a GUI.
Command Enter the following in Exchange Management Shell:
Get-PublicFolder –Identity &amp;quot;\Root Folder Name&amp;quot; -Recurse | Add-PublicFolderAdministrativePermission -User &amp;quot;ctitus&amp;quot; -AccessRights AllExtendedRights</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encore Bandit II/III Connection Instructions</title>
      <link>/encore-bandit-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 14:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/encore-bandit-connection/</guid>
      <description>These steps will show you how to connect to the encore bandit devices. I recently configured both a bandit II and a bandit III device for using a VPN over satellite. The devices are configured through a 9-pin serial port they call the “Supervisory Port”. I use a basic serial to USB adapter and putty to connect. All the white papers for this device are good, but the setup and login are not as clear as you would think, that said, below are the following steps I used to connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Website from Linux to IIS</title>
      <link>/move-website-linux-iis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 05:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/move-website-linux-iis/</guid>
      <description>This guide goes over how to Move Website from Linux to IIS. If you’re in the tech field, you probably see moving from Linux to IIS on a WordPress platform and immediately cringed.
Migration The database migration from MySQL to MS SQL is actually pretty easy since you just push it through a large query, but I didn’t really want to mess with it, so I stuck with MySQL.
Download and Install MySQL for Windows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FTP Credentials Required for WordPress Update to Plugins/Themes</title>
      <link>/ftp-credentials-required/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 22:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ftp-credentials-required/</guid>
      <description>If you are getting errors on a WordPress update that say you need FTP credentials, your apache install doesn’t have rights to do the changes. You could install vsftpd, but it is MUCH easier to just grant apache access to your WordPress.
Commands to grant access sudo chown -R apache:apache path/to/wordpress
Here is the syntax I used sudo chown -R apache:apache /var/www/html/
OR
sudo chown -R www-data:www-data /var/www/html/public_html
Afterward, you should not see the error asking for FTP Credentials again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slim Windows 10 Install</title>
      <link>/slim-reduce-windows-10-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 21:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slim-reduce-windows-10-install/</guid>
      <description>UPDATED POST https://christitus.com/2018/09/09/debloat-windows-10/ on a newer and improved way to debloat and slim Windows 10. This following commands slim down and reduce windows 10 footprint. Removing bloatware and cleaning up your system from windows apps. Run Powershell as Administrator and run the following script to Slim down and speed up your Windows 10 Install.NOTE: Get-AppxPackage -AllUsers line can be skiped if you want to keep Windows Store / Built-In Apps (Calculator / Bing News / Mail / etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check External IP in Linux Server</title>
      <link>/check-external-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 18:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/check-external-ip/</guid>
      <description>All these commands check external IP in Linux Terminal for any Linux system.
Commands Nice format for External IP curl -s checkip.dyndns.org | sed -e &#39;s/.*Current IP Address: //&#39; -e &#39;s/&amp;lt;.*$//&#39;
Short and Simple to remember curl ifconfig.co
For those with security concerns without using curl dig TXT +short o-o.myaddr.l.google.com @ns1.google.com | awk -F&#39;&amp;quot;&#39; &#39;{ print $2}&#39;
Any of these commands will achieve the same result, so pick which one you like best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Online Archive Requirements</title>
      <link>/exchange-online-archive-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 18:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exchange-online-archive-requirements/</guid>
      <description>This article goes over Exchange Online Archive Requirements and the headache of licensing for it. I recently completed a staged migration from exchange 2007 to exchange online. If you have any users over 50 GB you need the exchange online archive. Upload all your archive files using Azure copy (see https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/office365/securitycompliance/use-network-upload-to-import-pst-files for instructions). Afterward, make sure to check https://outlook.office365.com/owa/ to verify the archive emails. You may notice that their outlook doesn’t show the archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFC scannow error and Windows 10 corruption</title>
      <link>/sfc-scannow-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 02:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sfc-scannow-error/</guid>
      <description>If you run into SFC scannow error which cannot be repaired chances are you have some corrupt system components. The fastest way to fix this is by following these steps to repair your system.
Here is an example of the error you are seeing:

 Download Windows 10 ISO from https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windows10 Mount the ISO file by double-clicking on it. Open ‘Windows Powershell’ or ‘Command Prompt’ with Admin privileges (right click -&amp;gt; Run as Administrator) Let’s check the System Health first, by running these commands:  dism /online /cleanup-image /scanhealth dism /online /cleanup-image /checkhealth dism /online /cleanup-image /restorehealth   I’m sure that will give you an error stating that it could not perform the task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iDrac Dell Server (Off-Band Remote Access)</title>
      <link>/idrac-dell-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/idrac-dell-server/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a server freeze up when I wasn’t on-site and needed to power cycle it. I had configured iDrac before but it was not responsive. Here are some useful commands that can configure, reboot, and reset the iDrac function on Dell Servers. The commands below are run from a command prompt on the server (unless otherwise stated) in the (C:\Program Files\Dell\SysMgt\idrac) path.

Remote Commands (Workstation or another server)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GFI Archiver resource usage</title>
      <link>/gfi-archiver-resource-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 23:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gfi-archiver-resource-usage/</guid>
      <description>Does your GFI Archiver resource usage SQL process ballon over 8GB? If so, the following procedure will reduce usage by about half and fix many performance issues.
  Stop all MailArchiver and SQL services
  Create a backup of ..MailArchiverStoreDataproduct.config
  Edit product.config and add the following key within the &amp;lt;AppSettings&amp;gt; section: &amp;lt;add key=&amp;quot;MaxPoolSize&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;20&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
  Re-start the services
  *Note GFI has built-in scripts made to stop all NON-SQL services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raid Re-syncing Windows software raid</title>
      <link>/windows-software-raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 22:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-software-raid/</guid>
      <description>I want to preface this article in saying that I would never use a software raid in a business environment. However, recently I tried the windows software raid on a home theater PC. We recently had a power issue and caused the RAID 1 to go into resyncing status. Since it was about 2 TB of data, the resync would take several days and be causing performance issues. I found I could not break the raid or remove the mirror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy excel macros to all xls files on startup</title>
      <link>/deploy-excel-macros/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 15:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deploy-excel-macros/</guid>
      <description>To deploy excel macros on every excel file you open, you will need to create a personal file in your XLStart folder.
Here is a step-by-step  Create and test your macro Save as – Personal.xls (Macro-Enabled workbook) Copy the personal file to your C:Program Files\Microsoft Office\Office1#\XLStart folder Done!  I have no clue why the articles on TechNet and Microsoft’s Knowledge-base are so long when this is all you have to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove or Hide System Reserved Partition</title>
      <link>/hide-system-reserved-partition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 17:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hide-system-reserved-partition/</guid>
      <description>Does your system reserve partition have a drive letter? With these steps, you will Hide System Reserved Partition and no longer see it when browsing your computer.
Here is the fix using Diskpart:
 Load Command Prompt (cmd) Load Diskpart (diskpart) List Disks (list disk) Select Proper Disk (select disk #) List Partitions (list partition) Select Proper Partition (select partition #) List Volumes (list volume) NOTE: Look at Drive letter of system reserved volume Select the volume to hide (select volume #) Remove assigned disk letter (remote letter X)  With this, you should no longer see it, and you will Hide System Reserved Partition for good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Installation Error HRESULT E_FAIL</title>
      <link>/exchange-error-hresult-e_fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 21:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exchange-error-hresult-e_fail/</guid>
      <description>I was recently installing and configuring a new server with 32 processors and installing server 2008 Standard and Exchange 2007 SP1 Standard. During installation I received the following error:
HRESULT E_FAIL has been returned from a call to a COM component.
After finding a Knowledge-base article from Microsoft, I discovered Exchange 2007 SP1 doesn’t support installation on a server with more than 24 processors but is perfectly fine updating and running on a server with more than 24 processors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the find command Linux Terminal</title>
      <link>/find-command-linux-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 20:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/find-command-linux-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Here is the syntax for using the find command Linux terminal. The following commands are great to have in your back pocket when looking for specific files or directories.
How to find a file from the root directory and check the entire system:
find / -name filename.ext
See directory structure without files (requires tree use yum or apt-get to install)
tree -d /var/www/
Note: if you don’t include the -d it will list ALL files and folders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Anti-Spam SCL in Microsoft Exchange</title>
      <link>/anti-spam-scl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 16:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/anti-spam-scl/</guid>
      <description>This post goes over setting the Anti-Spam SCL in Microsoft Exchange. I typically recommend leaving the Delete and Reject settings alone, but change the Move Message to Junk if the user is reporting a high amount of spam making it to his inbox. This is done with the command below SCLJunkThreshold.
SCL (Spam Confidence Level) determines what to do with a message
Default Exchange Values 9 = Delete Message with no NDR&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; 7= Reject Message with NDR&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; 5= Move Message to Junk Mail in Mailbox</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take ownership of an entire drive in Windows</title>
      <link>/take-ownership-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 16:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/take-ownership-windows/</guid>
      <description>The commands below will show you how to take ownership of an entire drive. Here is a simple script to accomplish just that.
Option 1: Create a cmd file takeowner.cmd in notepad
Option 2: Type the following or past this in a command line prompt one line at a time
takeown /f %1 /r /d y&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; icacls %1 /grant administrators:F /t
Please Note: This will take a large amount of time on big drives</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outlook Security Certificate is invalid</title>
      <link>/outlook-security-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 21:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outlook-security-certificate/</guid>
      <description>The following article fixes the Outlook security certificate error your users get when they connect to your exchange server internally. This is typically from installing a 3rd party SSL Certificate.
(Original Article Link: http://community.spiceworks.com/how_to/show/48384-outlook-the-name-of-the-security-certificate-is-invalid-or-does-not-match-the-name-of-the-site)
Issue: Outlook anywhere works fine with third party cert, but internal Outlook clients get cert error with NETBIOS name of Exchange server.
Example: https://NetBIOS_name.contoso.com/autodiscover/autodiscover.xml
Note: I tested this on Exchange 2010 as well.
Outlook Security Certificate Resolution Change the URLs for the appropriate Exchange 2007 components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework 3.5 Update Fail</title>
      <link>/framework-3-5-update-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 18:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/framework-3-5-update-fail/</guid>
      <description>If you are having dot Net Framework 3.5 Update installation issues, then run the following commands to clear up the issue with the updates.
Event log showed **Error 1325.’Microsoft.NET’ is not a valid short file name. **
Create PowerShell Script file .ps1 Note: PowerShell must be installed check windows installed updates from appwiz.cpl
`# determine the framework and ebs guids. these will be unique for each install$productskey = &amp;ldquo;HKLM:SOFTWAREClassesInstallerProducts&amp;quot;$installedproducts = get-childitem $productskey$guidstofix = 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Windows Update error in Windows Vista</title>
      <link>/fix-windows-update-vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 17:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fix-windows-update-vista/</guid>
      <description>This article goes over the step-by-step instructions on how to fix windows update in windows vista. Using the following solution will fix the issue: (Note: I didn’t follow all these instructions and found that just stopping the Crypto service and deleting catroot2 folder was sufficient.)
You can try to register the following DLLs if Windows Update service is not starting up or having some issue updating/running Windows Updates:
 Create a batch file and copy the following contents in it and then double click on it to register modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing or Adding 9 to Dial out on VeriFone VX510</title>
      <link>/verifone-vx510-add-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 17:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/verifone-vx510-add-9/</guid>
      <description>Using the following steps to add or remove a 9 when using the VeriFone VX510 to process credit cards.

Step-by-Step Instructions  First go into Quick Setup (6 on pad) Password is 1 Alpha Alpha 66831 Select Phone Edit to add or remove 9 and then exit Done!  Now run a couple tests to verify that is properly dialing out on your VeriFone VX510. Once done you don’t have to worry about it failing when dialing out any longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing .NET Framework 3.5 / 3.0 / 2.0 Error 0x800F0906</title>
      <link>/error-0x800f0906/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 19:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/error-0x800f0906/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had error 0x800F0906 when doing a dot net framework update. http://support.microsoft.com/kb/2734782 Note: You could take this resolution further and push it out via network script if needed. Make sure to copy the Windows 8 DVD to a local network drive before attempting.
To resolve this problem, use one of the following methods, as appropriate for the error code that you are receiving.
Error code: 0x800F0906 This error code occurs because the computer cannot download the required files from Windows Update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannot Rename Folders on mapped drive</title>
      <link>/rename-folders-mapped-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 21:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rename-folders-mapped-drive/</guid>
      <description>This error message is displayed and I cannot rename folders on the mapped drive. By making a group policy change I was able to make this error go away.
The drive that this file or folder is stored on does not allow long file names, or names containing blanks or any of the following characters: / : , ; * ? &amp;lt; &amp;gt; |
Solution: Create a GPO to fix To resolve this problem, turn off Fast Logon Optimization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Screen RDP and various Remote Desktop Session hotkeys</title>
      <link>/full-screen-rdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 21:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/full-screen-rdp/</guid>
      <description>Here are all the hotkeys I use regularly when doing Full Screen RDP.
Full Screen RDP Hotkey:
Ctrl + Alt + Pause/Break Key
Activate Connection Bar:
Ctrl + Alt + Home
Send Ctrl+Alt+Del on Remote Computer
Ctrl + Alt + End
Simulate Alt+Tab on Remote Computer
Alt + Page Up/Page Down
Windows Key Press on Remote Computer
Alt + Home
I often find myself using these hotkeys to move around, but these are needed especially when you have a locked up program in an RDP session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GFI MailArchiver MAIS Queue Folder has tons of emails stuck</title>
      <link>/mais-queue-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 16:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mais-queue-folder/</guid>
      <description>The Import service can get stuck and this will stop all the mail in the MAIS Queue Folder. These are the emails that have not been processed and added to GFI Archiver yet, so do not delete them. Below is the fix on how I restored the import service and processed all the stuck email.
The Fix Deleted all files EXCEPT for *.eml from C:\Program Files (x86)\GFIMailArchiver\MAIS\Queue
Renamed all *.eml files to *.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving GFI MailArchiver to another server</title>
      <link>/moving-gfi-mailarchiver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 16:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/moving-gfi-mailarchiver/</guid>
      <description>The following walkthrough shows you the process of moving GFI MailArchiver to another server. These KB articles will assist you in the moving and migration of this server. The process is very involved and requires copying all the data files over to the new server. Afterward, backing up every single SQL database (archive store) and detaching/copying them. From there you reattach the stores and reinstall GFI MailArchiver on the new server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring SQL Authentication</title>
      <link>/configuring-sql-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 16:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/configuring-sql-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Configuring SQL Authentication can be tricky at times, and this is a great article that goes over the two types of authentication in SQL. I find some programs interface better with direct SQL authentication when Windows Authentication fails for any reason.
Note: This article is taken from http://kb.gfi.com/articles/SkyNet_Article/How-to-configure-SQL-Server-2005-2008-to-accept-SQL-Authentication and all credit goes to them for the writing. I’m posting it here simply as a reference in case there _site changes the above link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could not continue installation because update is pending</title>
      <link>/update-is-pending/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 19:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/update-is-pending/</guid>
      <description>When installing a program I kept getting the prompt below that an update is pending. Even after a restart, this would display, therefore I changed these registry keys to clear up the issue.
 Microsoft Server setup cannot continue because a restart from a previous installation or update is pending.
 The Fix for an update is pending The following Registry keys control this error message. If you have rebooted and are still experiencing this issue, clear out these keys and relaunch your installer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assigning Client Access Licenses without EBS Administration Console</title>
      <link>/assigning-client-access-licenses-without-ebs-administration-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 22:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assigning-client-access-licenses-without-ebs-administration-console/</guid>
      <description>This is a workaround for EBS Administration Console that can no longer launch or has errors on launch. Consequently, Microsoft put the Licensing in this Console only, and no other GUI exists for it. However, that is why Powershell exists, and here are the commands to manage all your CALs in your network.
Step-by-Step Guide  Open Powershell on Management Server. (Start -&amp;gt;All Programs -&amp;gt; Windows Powershell 1.0) Type this at command prompt: Add-PsSnapin Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Store not loading (On Domain)</title>
      <link>/windows-store-not-loading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 17:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-store-not-loading/</guid>
      <description>After joining my computer to the domain windows store would not load. I first had to re-enable UAC because of a GPO and that fixed launching the metro apps. I was still having the issue with Windows Store not loading and this fixed it.
Symptoms First, if you’re getting shut out of the store (“Can’t connect to the Store right now” kind of messages) &amp;amp; on a corporate, managed machine (you’ll see ‘Managed by your system administrator’ in Windows Update) – plus getting stuff like this in event viewer:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Refresh PC Setting</title>
      <link>/windows-refresh-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 16:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-refresh-pc/</guid>
      <description>Using Windows Refresh PC now solves the common problem, that PCs get infected with viruses and require you to either reload it from the disc or recovery partition. Sometimes people lost the disc, re-partitioned their drives, or simply had their hard drive fail. This leads to installing windows from scratch and hunting down all your drivers.
That is all changing in Windows 8, they are including a “Refresh” option and a “Remove everything and Re-install Windows” option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange on Primary Domain Controller Slow Reboot and Startup</title>
      <link>/exchange-primary-domain-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 20:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exchange-primary-domain-controller/</guid>
      <description>If you had the misfortune of installing Exchange on Primary Domain Controller you will experience some pain when doing a reboot. Typically it will take 10-15 minutes before it restarts and up to 30 minutes to start the Microsoft Exchange Information Store. Consequently, what is really happening in the background is the IS service is being terminated incorrectly on shutdown and the store is left in a “DIRTY” shutdown state. This is very bad on several levels and can cause the Store to corrupt and not start at all, which can be catastrophic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix for Kernel Panic in Mac OSX</title>
      <link>/kernel-panic-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 22:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kernel-panic-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>Follow these steps to fix a kernel panic in Mac OSX. However, if this doesn’t fix the issue, there is a good chance the motherboard is damaged and you need to send it to Apple.
1) SMC RESETTING  Shut down the computer. Plug in the MagSafe power adapter to a power source, connecting it to the Mac if its not already connected. On the built-in keyboard, press the (left side) Shift-Control-Option keys and the power button at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting your business from hacking groups</title>
      <link>/hacking-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 16:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacking-groups/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading a very good article from ABA journal (The Hacktivists)about computer security and the pitfalls that many companies which fall prey to hacking groups. This is probably the hundredth company to be hacked by Anonymous but was a particularly devastating attack because it ruined not only the company but the lives of several employees.
 Security holes hackers use  Outdated servers (Running old service packs, not updating critical updates, etc…) Custom-made content management system (If you spent more than 30k on a website you probably have one of these, and they never or rarely get updated security wise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Error 1327. Invalid Drive” or “Error 1325 – not a valid short file name” Fix</title>
      <link>/valid-short-file-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 20:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/valid-short-file-name/</guid>
      <description>If you are installing a program and receiving a pop-up message during installation of valid short file name this applies to you. I removed a drive from my computer and had this happen to me.
Steps to Fix “not a valid short file name”   Click Start, and then click Run.
  In the Open box, type regedit, and then click OK.
  Under Registry Editor, locate the following registry key: HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Explorer\Shell Folders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release and Renew IP in OS X</title>
      <link>/release-and-renew-ip-in-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 18:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/release-and-renew-ip-in-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I recently had some issues where a bridged virtual machine in osx would disconnect my osx side network connection. A simple release and renew would fix this. Simply open up Terminal in OSX and type:
 sudo ifconfig en0 down
  sudo ifconfig en0 up
 Obviously if you are renewing another interface other than your Ethernet port, en0 would need to be changed to the corresponding short name of the interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Windows 7 from installing device drivers from Windows Update</title>
      <link>/keep-windows-7-from-installing-device-drivers-from-windows-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 15:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/keep-windows-7-from-installing-device-drivers-from-windows-update/</guid>
      <description>I find a very annoying feature of Windows 7 is every device you install by default searches windows update. This makes installing devices a lot longer than it needs to be. Follow these steps to make windows search your computer first and then Windows Update if needed.
  Right Click My Computer from Start Menu and select “Properties”
  Click “Advanced System Settings”
  Select Hardware Tab, and click “Device Installation Settings”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archiving and Reducing Exchange Mailboxes and Stores (Part 2)</title>
      <link>/archiving-and-reducing-exchange-mailboxes-and-stores-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 21:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/archiving-and-reducing-exchange-mailboxes-and-stores-part-2/</guid>
      <description>You have analyzed your current exchange store and deciding to buy a 3rdparty solution so your users can maintain the large amount of emails they are accustomed to and retain all emails for legal/business purposes, and here are the options.
 Buy the Barracuda Message Archiver ( website link: http://www.barracudanetworks.com/ns/products/archiver-overview.php) which is a really simple installation and maintenance. I have used this before, and it gets the job done. I did have issues with restoring emails after being exported, but after some conversion and importing to pst files it worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archiving and Reducing Exchange Mailboxes and Stores (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/archiving-and-reducing-exchange-mailboxes-and-stores-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 22:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/archiving-and-reducing-exchange-mailboxes-and-stores-part-1/</guid>
      <description>With todays reliance on email, many people use outlook as there filing system. Its not to uncommon to find 10GB+ mailboxes. This is becoming a common problem for many exchange administrators because they have no way to deal with the shear size of these mailboxes. Outlook archive system isn’t sufficiant, because most time the PSTs it creates do not properly archive and isn’t centralally located which causes a nightmare when looking for archived emails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Outlook Anywhere in Group Policy Object (GPO)</title>
      <link>/disable-outlook-anywhere-in-group-policy-object-gpo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 15:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/disable-outlook-anywhere-in-group-policy-object-gpo/</guid>
      <description>By default the standard outlk12.adm templates do not come with a configuration of Outlook Anywhere. You can configure the “Configure Outlook Anywhere user interface options” options to disable or grey out the settings. However, this DOES NOT disable Outlook anywhere, just user interaction with it.
You will need to download a new administrative template that Microsoft released in this hotfix. If you don’t like reading Microsoft’s wonderful support site instructions or Microsoft changes their support site after this blog post, here is the file and instructions paraphrased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Target Specific People or Computers with Item-Level Targeting in GPOs</title>
      <link>/target-specific-people-or-computers-with-item-level-targeting-in-gpos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 21:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/target-specific-people-or-computers-with-item-level-targeting-in-gpos/</guid>
      <description>Using Group Policy Objects can be a huge time saver, but if used improperly can be a big headache. Once you’ve messed around with GPO settings enough, you quickly figure out that you need to create new GPOs for specific programs, events, etc… that are not all in one GPO. This gives you a lot more flexibility and makes it very easy to track down troublesome GPO related issues when done properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Matters “Database Not Found”</title>
      <link>/time-matters-database-not-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 21:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/time-matters-database-not-found/</guid>
      <description>Typically this is because it is pointed to the wrong database. I’ve also had instances where the installation was corrupted and after a reinstall it would blank out the Main SQL Server causing this error message. Here is how I resolved the issue.
First, enter the Set File Locations Utility. This can be done by adding the “/s” switch on the Time Matters shortcut, See screenshot below.
[singlepic id=725 w=200 h=300 float=center]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force Network Connection Priority</title>
      <link>/force-network-connection-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 19:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/force-network-connection-priority/</guid>
      <description>This describes how to have an adapter take priority of all internet traffic over another. For instance, you have 2 different networks on a single computer, and the wired connection does all your internal communications, but you want the wireless adapter to do all outgoing internet applications (iexplore, firefox, etc…).
Set the Interface Metric
 -Open Network Connections (ncpa.cpl)
  -Open the Network Connection to take priority (Right click desired connection -&amp;gt; Properties)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force Application to use one network connection</title>
      <link>/force-application-to-use-one-network-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 19:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/force-application-to-use-one-network-connection/</guid>
      <description>There is an application called ForceBindIP that allows you to bind certain applications to network connections. It doesn’t work for all applications, but most of them. It is also a bit glitchy in Vista and 7.
Download ForceBindIP
Write down your IP Addresses. I use a wired and wireless connection.
 -Run -&amp;gt; cmd
  -ipconfig
 Modify your Application shortcut’s target window
 -Add forcebindip ipaddress in front of “C:applicationpathexecutable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Exchange Server Version (Service Pack)</title>
      <link>/finding-exchange-server-version-service-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 20:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finding-exchange-server-version-service-pack/</guid>
      <description>There is a couple different methods to finding the version of your exchange server.
File System %Program Files%MicrosoftExchange Serverbin folder (different for 2003) and right click store.exe -&amp;gt; Detail Tab -&amp;gt; Version
——-OR——–
Exchange Management Console Go to Server Configuration -&amp;gt; Hub Transport -&amp;gt; Look at Version column (Exchange 2007)
——-OR——–
Exchange Management Shell type get-exchangeserver
Write down the Version number and find it on this list. It will provide you with the proper service pack and date of exchange server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Database File in SQL</title>
      <link>/grow-database-file-in-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 15:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/grow-database-file-in-sql/</guid>
      <description>I use both SQL Express 2005 on a server and SQL 2008 on another server. The following script is nice to manually grow a file. By default, SQL auto-grows database files by 10% when it runs low on space. In most cases this is fine, but I’m a perfectionist and hate receiving errors about low DB Space in my SCE (System Center Essentials) console.
 use OperationsManager
  declare @dbname nvarchar(300)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Server Backup (BackupExec, NTbackup, Acronis True Image, etc…)</title>
      <link>/windows-server-backup-backupexec-ntbackup-acronis-true-image-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 16:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-server-backup-backupexec-ntbackup-acronis-true-image-etc/</guid>
      <description>I will walk through the various backup solutions out there for businesses. Most of the big names in the backup world are very good at backups, however they must be used properly. If using Windows Server 2003, I’d recommend Acronis True Image for any file systems and NTbackup for the exchange backup or other servers. If using Windows Server 2008, I’d recommend Acronis True Image for any servers, and Acronis® Recovery™ for Microsoft Exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Redundancy in Exchange (Cloud, Relay, and Multiple MX Records)</title>
      <link>/email-redundancy-in-exchange-cloud-relay-and-multiple-mx-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 21:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/email-redundancy-in-exchange-cloud-relay-and-multiple-mx-records/</guid>
      <description>Many small and medium businesses do not have any email redundancy, and in today’s IT environment that is unacceptable. There is 3 widely used methods for never missing or having downtime for email. Depending on the size of your business there are some that make more sense than others.
Business Solutions
 Cloud Email – You can host your email off-site. Recommended Vendors. Rackspace.com or Intermedia.net Pros: Disaster prevention, Archiving, Spam filtering, and Automated Backups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Management Shell (EMS)</title>
      <link>/exchange-management-shell-ems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 20:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exchange-management-shell-ems/</guid>
      <description>Exchange Management Shell is the core of Microsoft Exchange. The GUI was an after thought, especially in Exchange 2007. Here are some useful commands that I use often.
Export Company to PSTs
 Get-Mailbox -OrganizationalUnit SBSUsers | Export-Mailbox -PSTFolderPath C:pathtosave -BadItemLimit 10000 -ExcludeFolders “Junk E-Mail”,”Deleted Items” -StartDate “01/01/2009 00:01:00”
 This is useful for moving an entire exchange store into PST format. This can be used for Exchange to External mail system migrations, or just to have a backup to access mailboxes at that point in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESEUTIL Proper usage, and when to use it.</title>
      <link>/eseutil-proper-usage-and-when-to-use-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 05:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eseutil-proper-usage-and-when-to-use-it/</guid>
      <description>ESEUTIL is a utility to repair, check, and defrag Microsoft exchange stores. Before using ESEUTIL you must unmount your exchange store and be prepared to have downtime.
ESEUTIL /d “C:ExchangeStorePathstore.edb” (Defrag)
Note: I’d rarely recommend using this defrag option, but in certain instances when exchange stores are merged or drastically changed it can be beneficial. This is an OFFLINE defrag and should not be used for frequent maintenance. I’ve seen people make big mistakes by pulling a perfectly good exchange store offline to try and squeeze an extra 10 GB out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>