<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Chris Titus Tech | Tech Content Creator</title>
    <link>https://christitus.com/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Chris Titus Tech | Tech Content Creator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:14:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christitus.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You are NOT safe in Windows</title>
      <link>https://christitus.com/not-safe-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:14:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christitus.com/not-safe-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all the Microsoft Windows users from all the Technicians that work on this operating system. Without your continued use, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-windows-not-secure&#34;&gt;Why is Windows NOT secure?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legacy systems and a fundamental flaw in system design. It is far to easy to get system level access through a variety of methods. Let&amp;rsquo;s go over the systems that you can use to exploit a traditional Windows user, so you know what NOT to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;PowerShell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powershell is one of the most powerful tools in Windows, but it is at a cost. While it makes it incredibly easy to administrator and make modifications to massive amounts of systems quickly, it can be abused. Pretty much anything you want to do can be accomplished with Powershell. This is most evident in business systems where it is required to administer systems and even Office 365 in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;task-scheduler&#34;&gt;Task Scheduler&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many processes end up running at a system level in Task scheduler and something the core system relied heavily on. This can not be disabled and is always one of the biggest Achilles heels for Windows. I am often disabling tasks to debloat systems such as auto-submission tools Microsoft uses like Telemetry and even Defender bug reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-basic---vbs-scripts&#34;&gt;Visual Basic - .vbs scripts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VBS scripts often provide a level of scripting that isn&amp;rsquo;t possible with many other methods. While this is good in business, it is very bad for the end user. I designed a vbs script to migrate on-premises outlook mailboxes to O365 mailboxes so a thousand users wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to redownload all their emails. However this can easily be abused for those malicious actors out there. Be cautious of this loophole and any vbs script that runs on your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;group-policy&#34;&gt;Group Policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again this is used in many pro+ systems and even if you aren&amp;rsquo;t part of a domain can be abused by using &lt;code&gt;gpedit.msc&lt;/code&gt; to create a local policy that can run scripts, lock user features, and much more. Home users typically don&amp;rsquo;t have this functionally unless a hack is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want Group Polcy as a home user type the following in an elevated to Administrator prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;dism /online /norestart /add-package:&amp;#34;%SystemRoot%servicingPackages{{PackageFileName}}**
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;registry&#34;&gt;Registry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many things can be accomplished with the registry, such as auto login, and various hooks that can happen by just launching your web browser or windows explorer. Registry is basically the brain of windows and can be exploited easily to do pretty much anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-protect-yourself&#34;&gt;How to protect yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend hardening your system with just basic tools that do NOT run in the background, but disable many of the tools above. These tools are wonderful in the right hands, but world ending the wrong ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple free hardening tool on Github will disable many of these attack surfaces and do FAR more than any antivirus or internet security suite can, while also not adding ANY overhead or extra processes to your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HardenTools to disable services: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/securitywithoutborders/hardentools&#34;&gt;https://github.com/securitywithoutborders/hardentools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://christitus.com/images/2022/hardentools.png&#34; alt=&#34;harden&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;walkthrough-video&#34;&gt;Walkthrough Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bh8HqxxI4pc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.youtube.com/vi/Bh8HqxxI4pc/0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;youtube-video&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: YouTube Video - Hold Ctrl + Left Click to open in new window&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Linux</title>
      <link>https://christitus.com/secure-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 13:02:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christitus.com/secure-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article covers basic security and settings I do with every Linux installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;check-for-drovorub-malware&#34;&gt;Check for Drovorub Malware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://christitus.com/images/2020/drovorub/drovorub.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drovorub&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;touch testfile
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;echo “ASDFZXCV:hf:testfile” &amp;gt; /dev/zero
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If the testfile disappears&amp;hellip; you are infected&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;check-for-unsigned-kernel-modules&#34;&gt;Check for unsigned kernel modules&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;for mod in $(lsmod | tail -n +2 | cut -d&amp;#39; &amp;#39; -f1); do modinfo ${mod} | grep -q &amp;#34;signature&amp;#34; || echo &amp;#34;no signature for module: ${mod}&amp;#34; ; done
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you see vbox or nvidia modules, these are for VirtualBox and NVidia Drivers respectively&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;secure-boot&#34;&gt;Secure Boot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://christitus.com/images/2020/drovorub/secure-boot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;secure-boot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure Boot forces checks for kernel module signatures and is good not only for blocking Drovorub-style malware, but also prevents Evil Maid attacks as well. However, it can be complex and also make using bootable USB drives difficult. &lt;em&gt;Note: UEFI Boot Required&amp;hellip; No Legacy/CSM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;easy-way-to-install&#34;&gt;Easy Way to Install&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo mokutil --enable-validation # Remember the password!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo mokutil --sb-state # Checks if Secure Boot is enabled
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;*Note: I used the enable validation on Debian based systems and it worked right out of the box&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hard-way-to-install&#34;&gt;Hard Way to Install&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard way involves signing packages that aren&amp;rsquo;t stock which you might need on your system or if you dual boot. Check out the following guide from the ArchWiki: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Unified_Extensible_Firmware_Interface/Secure_Boot&#34;&gt;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Unified_Extensible_Firmware_Interface/Secure_Boot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;security-settings-for-all-linux-installs&#34;&gt;Security Settings for All Linux Installs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://christitus.com/images/github.png&#34; alt=&#34;github&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a github script to make this easier but I wanted to break down what this script does. Secure-Linux Project &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChrisTitusTech/secure-linux/blob/master/secure.sh&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ChrisTitusTech/secure-linux/blob/master/secure.sh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before running this script install ufw and fail2ban packages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script is broken into 3 parts: ufw, sysctl.conf modifications, and fail2ban. Ufw stands for Uncomplicated Firewall and is fantastic for adding to every install. This script opens http and https, while limiting SSH to only a couple connections per second. The sysctl modifications helps harden your system by preventing spoofing and man in the middle attacks. Fail2ban is the final piece and possibly my favorite. This package see any traffic that is failing authentication attempts repeatedly or is malicious in nature (DDoS) and records the IP then blocks it for a period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other things I&amp;rsquo;d recommend not mentioned&amp;hellip; SELinux! Look it up because it is amazing. You can also use this on debian if you&amp;rsquo;d like, but a smaller package called AppArmor is generally used on those types of distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a all inclusive guide on securing your Linux system, but it is a good starting point that I do on pretty much every computer. I highly recommend you take these instructions and expand them to suit your needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
