<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows on Chris Titus Tech</title>
    <link>/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows on Chris Titus Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 20:08:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Up Windows 10</title>
      <link>/clean-up-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 20:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clean-up-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will clean up Windows 10. This will include debloat, startup maintenance, system tweaks, and privacy settings. These 3 stages are broken down below and will help maintain a healthy Windows 10 system. I’d recommend re-running these steps every 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing file permissions using PowerShell</title>
      <link>/changing-file-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 15:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/changing-file-permissions/</guid>
      <description>Use the following script for changing file permissions using PowerShell. I use this script when command line takeown and icacls fail. Obviously, run from an elevated PowerShell prompt or by typing ‘powershell’ from elevated cmd.
The Script Change $folder to the base directory you want for changing permissions.
Please note, you can use network UNC paths for this or a simple C:.
$folder = &amp;quot;\\homeserver\users\&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; $users = get-childitem $folder&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Foreach ($user in $users) {&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; $acl = Get-Acl $user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a startup program to run as administrator</title>
      <link>/run-as-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 02:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/run-as-administrator/</guid>
      <description>The following script shows you how to launch a startup program to run as administrator in Windows 10. This fixes many programs that require elevation and you don’t want to launch manually every time.
Almost every online tutorial I came across said to run it as a scheduled task. This is very cumbersome and I hate it, however using the following method is easier and saves you time.
Create a Text file in shell:startup and put the following in it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>