<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on Chris Titus Tech</title>
    <link>/categories/miscellaneous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on Chris Titus Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 16:15:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CTT Newsletter – October 2019</title>
      <link>/ctt-newsletter-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ctt-newsletter-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>This is the first newsletter that I am sending out and is meant as a quick monthly recap of all the content that is provided. I don’t want to blow up your inbox with junk, but want to provide you extra value by linking tutorial guides and video playlists that may interest you. If you like this format and are not yet signed up, you can sign up at https://community.christitus.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigDaddyLinux Interview</title>
      <link>/bigdaddylinux-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 23:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bigdaddylinux-interview/</guid>
      <description>I had a great time chatting with Rocco from BDL and loved his interview style. I didn’t realize we talked for an hour and half, but had an absolute blast and will definitely jump in on some more of his live streams. Here is the interview:If you get a chance and want to see the other people he has interviewed, here is his YouTube channel and website:
 https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCtZRKfyvx7GUEi-Lr7f4Nxg https://www.bigdaddylinux.com  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 13 – European Union and YouTube</title>
      <link>/article-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article-13/</guid>
      <description>This is about Article 13 and Why it is actually great for YouTube as a company but will cause more censorship across the European Union.
The main debate is holding the sharing platform liable for any damages sustained. YouTube is angling to say they are protecting copyright holders due to their Content ID system and might be able to corner the marketplace.
There is a specific provision in Article 13 that I think Google will leverage and completely annihilate the competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stellar Data Recovery Standard Review</title>
      <link>/stellar-data-recovery-standard-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 14:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stellar-data-recovery-standard-review/</guid>
      <description>This is a review of the Standard version of Stellar Data Recovery software. I go over the cost, performance, and result of the recovery.
Features  Recovers data from multiple devices Sorts devices by folder Photo, Video, and Documents restored in Standard Edition  The features are good for the standard edition, and I have nothing bad to say about what is included. I have used various other pieces of software and for this price point, I was happy with the feature set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Plex plugin in FreeNAS</title>
      <link>/install-plex-plugin-freenas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 19:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/install-plex-plugin-freenas/</guid>
      <description>This is an in-depth installation and configuration of the Plex plugin in FreeNAS 11.2. I detail the installation of plex on FreeNAS Jail and configuration of using a share as a Plex mount point.
Plex plugin in FreeNAS Steps  Install Plex Plugin  Under Plugins -&amp;gt; Availiable   Set Static IP  Interface em0 (or your interface name), Static IP for Plex Server, and Netmask (/24 is 255.255.255.0)   Stop Plugin Edit Plex Jail – Mount Point – Note: This is only used if you want a share to add movies to your plex from another computer  Set Source Share (/mnt/sharename/) and Set Destination (I selected the media folder in the jail directory)   Edit Plex Jail – Edit Confiuration  Check VNET and Berkeley Packet Filter Set Default IPv4 Route to your Gateway or Router (Ex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Change Cortana Search</title>
      <link>/change-cortana-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 15:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/change-cortana-search/</guid>
      <description>This article goes over how to change Cortana search engine to display results in chrome instead of Microsoft Edge. Afterward, the second part requires you to install a chrome extension to search in Google instead of Bing. Check the links below for the source code to compile, download pre-compiled, or support the developer using Windows Store.
Video Walkthrough Links from Video  https://github.com/sylveon/SearchWithMyBrowser – GitHub Source and Compile Instructions https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9PPKNR9RK26R?ocid=badge – Windows Store Link from Developer https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup FreeNAS 11</title>
      <link>/setup-freenas-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 16:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/setup-freenas-11/</guid>
      <description>This article goes over how to setup FreeNAS 11 and configure it. These are the basic steps so you can have a reliable network storage at your house.
Steps to setup FreeNAS 11  Download FreeNAS stable from http://www.freenas.org/download-freenas-release/ Create Thumb drive from iso and Win32DiskImager https://sourceforge.net/projects/win32diskimager/  Note: DO NOT use Rufus or Yumi as these won’t create a bootable thumb drive   Install and Follow the Prompts Set Static IP Reboot Login to Web Interface with IP from Step 4 Set up Storage Pool Assign SMB Share  Make sure allow guest access is checked   Configure SMB Share Service  Auto-Start and Enabled Configure Guest user to be root   Test!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide: Using EOS Ledger App with Scatter Wallet</title>
      <link>/eos-ledger-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 18:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eos-ledger-app/</guid>
      <description>This video goes over using EOS Ledger App with Scatter Wallet. Within it shows how to add the EOS app to the ledger, generate ledger public key, create an account, and do transactions on the EOS blockchain using your ledger.
Considerations  Use a backup ledger in a secure location with the same seed words if you are storing a substantial amount of EOS. Ledger does not provide a private key and there is no tool to create a private key from your seed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect htaccess for WordPress</title>
      <link>/perfect-htaccess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perfect-htaccess/</guid>
      <description>This walks you through what your htaccess should look like in a WordPress Installation. I am a minimalist and believe you shouldn’t be using a ton of plugins that slow down your install when most of what you are looking to accomplish can be achieved with this file. Therefore, this htaccess will contain bad bot blocker, security optimizations, force https, and a variety of other optimizations. This will save you from installing about 5-10 plugins that would slow down your website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Complete Beginners Guide to Getting Started on the EOS Blockchain</title>
      <link>/the-complete-beginners-guide-to-getting-started-on-the-eos-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 19:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-complete-beginners-guide-to-getting-started-on-the-eos-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>This Guide shows you everything you need that will get started on the EOS blockchain. Creating Keys, wallet, account, and using dApps are all in this guide. The following videos will get you running EOS decentralized Apps.
Watch all EOS Videos from YouTube via Playlist here: Instructional EOS Videos for beginnersFirst Video Install a Linux terminal in Windows 10 afterward we will be able to build EOS tools in here. This is important to do as you can’t compile EOS natively in windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Stake EOS?</title>
      <link>/stake-eos-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 15:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stake-eos-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>This video goes over how to stake EOS for CPU, RAM, and bandwidth. It shows real-world examples of staking and unstaking EOS when utilizing the EOS dApps.
Staking Basics You can stake and unstake from many dApps, but my preferred method is using the EOS Toolkit and finalizing my amounts in there. Personally, I recommend 8 KB for RAM, 15 EOS for CPU, and .1 EOS for Net as this will give you the ability to play and use pretty much any decentralized app out right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you stay in Crypto? Is it Over or Just Beginning?</title>
      <link>/stay-crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 14:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stay-crypto/</guid>
      <description>This video is out there for anyone thinking about staying in crypto or getting into it. I give my introduction to cryptocurrency and a background about me and my experiences.
View All Videos / Content / Guides / Solutions @ https://www.christitus.com
About me 0:00-15+ years in the IT Field
-3 years of Computer Science
-Researched many crypto projects
-Early Bitcoin miner when you could mine on GPU
-Early Ethereum miner and entered @ $17</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SciDex ICO Review</title>
      <link>/scidex-ico-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scidex-ico-review/</guid>
      <description>This video goes over all the aspects of the SciDex ICO and grades it based on criteria that have made ICOs successful in the past.
Official Links Official Site/
Protocol Whitepaper
MarketSpace Whitepaper
4 Criteria for ICO Review   Real World Application
  Funding
  Tangible Progress
  Misc. Concerns
  Conclusion From the look of everything, I’m betting it will be another ICO Scam. There is a possibility I am just missing the entire point of this ICO, but everything I have seen just screams that this is a project going nowhere fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome missing www and how to fix it</title>
      <link>/google-chrome-update-69-address-bar-and-how-to-fix-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 20:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/google-chrome-update-69-address-bar-and-how-to-fix-it/</guid>
      <description>Chrome started rolling out update 69 at the beginning of this month (September 2018) causing a missing www in the address bar. There are two things this update did that you need to be aware of.
Google Chrome Update 69 Changes  Show trivial sub-domains (missing www in the address bar)  Fix: Type this in your address bar: chrome://flags/#omnibox-ui-hide-steady-state-url-scheme-and-subdomains Set to DISABLED   Chrome now defaults to SSL / HTTPS for all websites  So I didn’t realize this happened and launched a new ubuntu web server to find it unreachable with apache installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOS Account Creation and using Accounts on the blockchain</title>
      <link>/eos-account-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 20:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eos-account-creation/</guid>
      <description>I posted an article about EOS Titled “Why EOS is destined to fail?“. Shortly after, I received a couple responses from folks that said the chain is down or not working or just simply too hard to use. It made me scratch my head and after a couple minutes searching I really didn’t find too many articles outlining how EOS works, EOS Account creation, or how an average person can use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOS Dallas Presentation</title>
      <link>/eos-dallas-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 03:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eos-dallas-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Here is a recent presentation I gave at EOS Dallas. This was a brief overview of EOS Blockchain and some potential pitfalls in March of 2018
www.christitus.com/eosdallas
September 2018 Update:
Pros  ERC20 Token conversion was successful Brock Pierce was removed from his advisory role at Block.One (TLDR; He was accused of assaulting minors in his employment back in 2000 at Digital Entertainment Network.) Slow Development is no longer an issue because they have pushed out 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get rid of Amazon Fire Launcher without root access</title>
      <link>/amazon-fire-launcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 21:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/amazon-fire-launcher/</guid>
      <description>This How-To shows you how to get rid of Amazon Fire Launcher without root access. Amazon Fire 5.3.3 OS can’t be downgraded or rooted, and since the Fire tablet line auto-updates, this leads many folks with the horrible experience of using the Fire OS with their gimped store/subscriptions.
The process to use Google Services and Googles Store instead is a bit involved but entirely doable on the Fire Tablets without having to root it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating LDAP Credentials for Netscaler VPX 1000</title>
      <link>/update-netscaler-vpx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 15:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/update-netscaler-vpx/</guid>
      <description>This article shows you how to update LDAP credentials on the Netscaler VPX 1000. It goes over logging in, editing virtual server, and applying settings.
Login to the NetScaler Device Default User: nsroot Pass: nsroot (or password you changed it to)
Go to Netscaler gateway virtual server controlling your logins 
Click on LDAP Policy and select Edit Server 
Update the credentials under connection settings, and also test the new settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iDrac Dell Server (Off-Band Remote Access)</title>
      <link>/idrac-dell-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/idrac-dell-server/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a server freeze up when I wasn’t on-site and needed to power cycle it. I had configured iDrac before but it was not responsive. Here are some useful commands that can configure, reboot, and reset the iDrac function on Dell Servers. The commands below are run from a command prompt on the server (unless otherwise stated) in the (C:\Program Files\Dell\SysMgt\idrac) path.

Remote Commands (Workstation or another server)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy excel macros to all xls files on startup</title>
      <link>/deploy-excel-macros/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 15:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deploy-excel-macros/</guid>
      <description>To deploy excel macros on every excel file you open, you will need to create a personal file in your XLStart folder.
Here is a step-by-step  Create and test your macro Save as – Personal.xls (Macro-Enabled workbook) Copy the personal file to your C:Program Files\Microsoft Office\Office1#\XLStart folder Done!  I have no clue why the articles on TechNet and Microsoft’s Knowledge-base are so long when this is all you have to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting your business from hacking groups</title>
      <link>/hacking-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 16:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacking-groups/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading a very good article from ABA journal (The Hacktivists)about computer security and the pitfalls that many companies which fall prey to hacking groups. This is probably the hundredth company to be hacked by Anonymous but was a particularly devastating attack because it ruined not only the company but the lives of several employees.
 Security holes hackers use  Outdated servers (Running old service packs, not updating critical updates, etc…) Custom-made content management system (If you spent more than 30k on a website you probably have one of these, and they never or rarely get updated security wise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>