<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exchange Server 2003 on Chris Titus Tech</title>
    <link>/categories/exchange-server-2003/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exchange Server 2003 on Chris Titus Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 21:37:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/exchange-server-2003/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Archiving and Reducing Exchange Mailboxes and Stores (Part 2)</title>
      <link>/archiving-and-reducing-exchange-mailboxes-and-stores-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 21:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/archiving-and-reducing-exchange-mailboxes-and-stores-part-2/</guid>
      <description>You have analyzed your current exchange store and deciding to buy a 3rdparty solution so your users can maintain the large amount of emails they are accustomed to and retain all emails for legal/business purposes, and here are the options.
 Buy the Barracuda Message Archiver ( website link: http://www.barracudanetworks.com/ns/products/archiver-overview.php) which is a really simple installation and maintenance. I have used this before, and it gets the job done. I did have issues with restoring emails after being exported, but after some conversion and importing to pst files it worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Exchange Server Version (Service Pack)</title>
      <link>/finding-exchange-server-version-service-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 20:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finding-exchange-server-version-service-pack/</guid>
      <description>There is a couple different methods to finding the version of your exchange server.
File System %Program Files%MicrosoftExchange Serverbin folder (different for 2003) and right click store.exe -&amp;gt; Detail Tab -&amp;gt; Version
——-OR——–
Exchange Management Console Go to Server Configuration -&amp;gt; Hub Transport -&amp;gt; Look at Version column (Exchange 2007)
——-OR——–
Exchange Management Shell type get-exchangeserver
Write down the Version number and find it on this list. It will provide you with the proper service pack and date of exchange server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Server Backup (BackupExec, NTbackup, Acronis True Image, etc…)</title>
      <link>/windows-server-backup-backupexec-ntbackup-acronis-true-image-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 16:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-server-backup-backupexec-ntbackup-acronis-true-image-etc/</guid>
      <description>I will walk through the various backup solutions out there for businesses. Most of the big names in the backup world are very good at backups, however they must be used properly. If using Windows Server 2003, I’d recommend Acronis True Image for any file systems and NTbackup for the exchange backup or other servers. If using Windows Server 2008, I’d recommend Acronis True Image for any servers, and Acronis® Recovery™ for Microsoft Exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Redundancy in Exchange (Cloud, Relay, and Multiple MX Records)</title>
      <link>/email-redundancy-in-exchange-cloud-relay-and-multiple-mx-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 21:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/email-redundancy-in-exchange-cloud-relay-and-multiple-mx-records/</guid>
      <description>Many small and medium businesses do not have any email redundancy, and in today’s IT environment that is unacceptable. There is 3 widely used methods for never missing or having downtime for email. Depending on the size of your business there are some that make more sense than others.
Business Solutions
 Cloud Email – You can host your email off-site. Recommended Vendors. Rackspace.com or Intermedia.net Pros: Disaster prevention, Archiving, Spam filtering, and Automated Backups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Management Shell (EMS)</title>
      <link>/exchange-management-shell-ems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 20:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exchange-management-shell-ems/</guid>
      <description>Exchange Management Shell is the core of Microsoft Exchange. The GUI was an after thought, especially in Exchange 2007. Here are some useful commands that I use often.
Export Company to PSTs
 Get-Mailbox -OrganizationalUnit SBSUsers | Export-Mailbox -PSTFolderPath C:pathtosave -BadItemLimit 10000 -ExcludeFolders “Junk E-Mail”,”Deleted Items” -StartDate “01/01/2009 00:01:00”
 This is useful for moving an entire exchange store into PST format. This can be used for Exchange to External mail system migrations, or just to have a backup to access mailboxes at that point in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESEUTIL Proper usage, and when to use it.</title>
      <link>/eseutil-proper-usage-and-when-to-use-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 05:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eseutil-proper-usage-and-when-to-use-it/</guid>
      <description>ESEUTIL is a utility to repair, check, and defrag Microsoft exchange stores. Before using ESEUTIL you must unmount your exchange store and be prepared to have downtime.
ESEUTIL /d “C:ExchangeStorePathstore.edb” (Defrag)
Note: I’d rarely recommend using this defrag option, but in certain instances when exchange stores are merged or drastically changed it can be beneficial. This is an OFFLINE defrag and should not be used for frequent maintenance. I’ve seen people make big mistakes by pulling a perfectly good exchange store offline to try and squeeze an extra 10 GB out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>