<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XenServer on Chris Titus Tech</title>
    <link>/categories/xenserver/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XenServer on Chris Titus Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:14:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/xenserver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Xen Orchestra</title>
      <link>/how-to-install-xen-orchestra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-install-xen-orchestra/</guid>
      <description>This article shows you how to install Xen Orchestra and use the interface via the web. XOA is a very powerful addition to XenServer as it brings auto-updates and making it easier to manage entire farms.
Step-by-Step Guide  Login to your XenServer via PuTTy OR through XenCenter console Type bash -c &amp;quot;$(curl -s http://xoa.io/deploy)&amp;quot;  Enter a new IP where you will access XOA from web Wait for this to finish you will see XOA VM popup Note: This may take a couple hours if XOA servers are downloading slow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create iSCSI SR in XenServer</title>
      <link>/create-iscsi-sr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 16:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/create-iscsi-sr/</guid>
      <description>This guide goes over how to Create iSCSI SR on Xen to connect to an iSCSI target. Here is the step-by-step and a video walkthrough, which includes setting up iSCSI in FreeNAS.
Requirements  Multiple XenServers (2+) in a Pool iSCSI target (Check out FreeNAS in the video below for setting one up) At LEAST a gigabit environment   Step-by-Step Guide to Create iSCSI SR  Open and Connect to XenCenter / XCP-ng Center Select Pool and Click New Storage Make sure iSCSI is selected Name Storage Select either provisioning methods Enter IP Address / Authentication (if needed) / Click Scan Target Host Pick IQN / LUN from your storage device  Note: When Selecting IQN_, make sure you select your SAN if you are using a dedicated network_   Finish  Video Walkthrough In the end, we now have a centralized storage system that all our hosts can put their VMs on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XenServer cannot connect in XenCenter or XCP-ng Center</title>
      <link>/xenserver-cannot-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/xenserver-cannot-connect/</guid>
      <description>Having problems and your XenServer cannot connect to XenCenter? Did you have high availability enabled? If you answered yes to both these questions here is how you get your XenServer back online and functioning properly.

Step-by-Step Guide  PuTTy into the XenServer Pool Master run the following commands:  xe pool-ha-disable_Note: If this fails try ha-disable force below_
xe host-emergency-ha-disable force=true&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; xe pool-emergency-transition-to-master --force
Note: This will force the pool and slaves to reinitialize with the pool master</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XCP-ng / XenServer – Your First Virtual Machine Installation</title>
      <link>/xenserver-xcp-ng-first-vm-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 18:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/xenserver-xcp-ng-first-vm-install/</guid>
      <description>This video goes through setting up a Virtual Machine in XenServer / XCP-ng in a lab environment. If you want to experiment with in detail with XenServer, I highly recommend you download XCP-ng from their official website. This is a community-powered version of XenServer with ALL FEATURES ENABLED. XenServer from Citrix has recently started going away from its open-source roots and as a result, has begun locking features behind a paywall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Introduction</title>
      <link>/virtualization-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 21:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtualization-introduction/</guid>
      <description>This is a virtualization introduction and when you should be using it. In the follow-up videos, I will go into using the hypervisor, creating VMs and maintenance.
Now that you understand what it is and if you want to start getting your feet wet, please check out my other video to start installing your hypervisor and launching your first virtual machine here. I highly recommend starting out with VMware as it used the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reattach LVM after a reinstalling XenServer</title>
      <link>/reattach-lvm-xenserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 16:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reattach-lvm-xenserver/</guid>
      <description>This article describes how to reattach LVM or a local Storage repository on XenServer. The XenServer database has become corrupt or your XenServer does not see the local SR.
Instructions   Do a pvscan to get the Universally Unique Identifier (UUID) of an existing SR on a local disk. In this example uses UUID 39baf126-a535-549f-58d6-feeda55f7801:
pvscan
  Output: PV /dev/sda3 VG VG_XenStorage-39baf126-a535-549f-58d6-feeda55f7801 lvm2 [66.87 GB / 57.87 GB free]&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Total: 1 [66.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XenServer tapdisk experienced an error</title>
      <link>/xenserver-tapdisk-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 16:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/xenserver-tapdisk-error/</guid>
      <description>When re-attaching a SR on a fresh VM, I ran into this XenServer tapdisk error. I ran the following from XenServer console to eject all CD drives on that host. I was then able to start the VM with the old image.
xe vm-cd-eject --multiple
If your XenCenter hangs or becomes unresponsive, you can also reset the toolstack from console from a PuTTy session or if XenCenter console is working running the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citrix XenCenter error “Could not create SSL/TLS Secure Channel”</title>
      <link>/citrix-xencenter-error-ssl-secure-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 14:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/citrix-xencenter-error-ssl-secure-channel/</guid>
      <description>Running the following commands will fix the XenCenter Error. You are typically encountering this error because Windows 10 requires stronger encryption, consequently, this is prevalent on older XenServer installations. I encountered this on XenServer 6.0.
Commands  Putty in using SSH service xapissl stop mv /etc/xensource/xapi-ssl.pem /etc/xensource/xapi-ssl.pem.bak /opt/xensource/libexec/generate_ssl_cert &amp;quot;/etc/xensource/xapi-ssl.pem&amp;quot; &#39;10.100.0.40&#39; service xapissl start xe-toolstack-restart  Where you see 10.100.0.40 this is the IP of your XenServer that you are connecting to (not VM ips).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>