<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>youtube on Chris Titus Tech | Tech Content Creator</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/youtube/</link>
    <description>Recent content in youtube on Chris Titus Tech | Tech Content Creator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Will Watch Ads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/you-will-watch-ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/you-will-watch-ads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are massive changes coming to the internet and youtube in the form of Ads and the death of the ad blocker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is happening in several different ways in the coming months. Let&amp;rsquo;s go over what I see as inevitable and talk about workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;youtube-detecting-ad-blockers&#34;&gt;YouTube detecting Ad Blockers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2023/you-will-watch-ads/yt-ads.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube is testing blocking ad blockers like so many different news websites do right now. This will bring the rise of secondary viewers and the use of other sites likes odysee or freetube. These sites rely on YouTube&amp;rsquo;s API and public sync, which will also be in the cross-hairs very soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/technology/youtube-tests-blocking-videos-unless-you-disable-ad-blockers/&#34;&gt;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/technology/youtube-tests-blocking-videos-unless-you-disable-ad-blockers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chromium-changes&#34;&gt;Chromium changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s Manifest 3 is almost here in June 2023 and that will hamstring all Ad blockers. Most ad blockers and privacy plugins rely on Manifest 2 and with version 3 being activated they will sunset version 2. How will this affect Firefox users? Will they require google and youtube viewers to be compliant with version 3? Time will tell&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was a good writeup from adguard on manifest v3: &lt;a href=&#34;https://adguard.com/en/blog/firefox-manifestv3-chrome-adblocking.html&#34;&gt;https://adguard.com/en/blog/firefox-manifestv3-chrome-adblocking.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR; Firefox will see more adoption and regular chrome ad extensions will be limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-access-and-3rd-party-sites&#34;&gt;API Access and 3rd Party sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can already see an ocean of comments that I will x, y, or z instead of youtube and google. The main issue is most alternatives rely on Google and it&amp;rsquo;s VERY open API. Sites like Odysee and many youtube apps not playing ads, rely on the API to SYNC the youtube videos to their servers. These services are on borrowed time and I&amp;rsquo;m shocked they haven&amp;rsquo;t already been taken down or at least restricted access for syncing YouTube content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-custom-dns-like-pihole&#34;&gt;What About Custom DNS like pihole?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ad block through custom dns always works, but it works too well. The reason we use ublock orgin or a browser based ad block is to keep the sites loading correctly and apps functioning properly. It would be trivial for Google to put roadblocks in the way of loading youtube if you block adsense. A good solution, but not the best when it comes to the user experience and using Google Ad supported products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;walkthrough-video&#34;&gt;Walkthrough Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oQL9dVsEXT0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube Comment Scams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/youtube-telegram-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/youtube-telegram-scams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YouTube telegram and whatsapp scams are everywhere in the comment section of every YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2023/youtube-telegram-scams/scam1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-the-scam-works&#34;&gt;How the scam works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They impersonate the creator of the channel in a giveaway scam. The end result is to extract money via shipping fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red Flags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never from an official email or the same name as creator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No creator uses whatsapp or telegram for communication. We&amp;rsquo;d just leave our email in the comment itself. &lt;em&gt;Note: scammers can&amp;rsquo;t do this because it would be caught by spam filters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shipping fees are high&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know of a YouTuber that has EVER charged fans for shipping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invoice isn&amp;rsquo;t from YouTuber and they request &amp;ldquo;Friends and Family&amp;rdquo; for faster processing because it is NON-REFUNDABLE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giveaways are rare and dangerous for the YouTuber. An example of this is &amp;ldquo;The Linux Experiment&amp;rdquo; did a Tuxedo computer giveaway and the entire channel was deleted by YouTube. I will never do a giveaway because of these dangers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-people-fall-for-these-scams&#34;&gt;Do people fall for these scams?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes - Here are screenshots from a victim that contacted me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2023/youtube-telegram-scams/victim1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amount lost - Notice that it was sent via &amp;ldquo;Friends and Family&amp;rdquo; Gift that is NON-REFUNDABLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2023/youtube-telegram-scams/victim2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick to give you to gift it? Faster Processing via bogus invoice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2023/youtube-telegram-scams/bogus-invoice.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Folks get caught up in the excitement of winning something and ignore these red flags. Emotions are how we all make bad decisions and why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t rush into these scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;walkthrough-video&#34;&gt;Walkthrough Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L1QM4blK-54&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
