<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google Chrome on Chris Titus Tech | Tech Content Creator</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/google-chrome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google Chrome on Chris Titus Tech | Tech Content Creator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 20:49:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/google-chrome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome missing www and how to fix it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/google-chrome-update-69-address-bar-and-how-to-fix-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 20:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/google-chrome-update-69-address-bar-and-how-to-fix-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chrome started rolling out update 69 at the beginning of this month (September 2018) causing a missing www in the address bar. There are two things this update did that you need to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-chrome-update-69-changes&#34;&gt;Google Chrome Update 69 Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show trivial sub-domains (missing www in the address bar)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix: Type this in your address bar:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chrome://flags/#omnibox-ui-hide-steady-state-url-scheme-and-subdomains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set to &lt;strong&gt;DISABLED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chrome now defaults to SSL / HTTPS for all websites&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So I didn’t realize this happened and launched a new ubuntu web server to find it unreachable with apache installed. After wasting a lot of time, more than I’m willing to tell you here, I found out the new version of chrome will default to https:// before everything unless you explicitly put http:// in the address bar. This includes IP addresses and the like. So make sure you have SSL certs updated otherwise you are going to have a bad time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-walkthrough&#34;&gt;Video Walkthrough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0O9TzNvVwR0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I typically love a lot of the Google projects and updates they do, but the missing www in the address bar left me a little puzzled and why they thought they needed to do it. On the plus side, I do like the new chrome tabs, so the entire update is not all bad. Also, the changes to default to secure sites has been a long time coming. There are many different reasons for this, but the fact is by forcing webmasters to use SSL and get secure is a good thing. These days non-secure http sites can easily be exploited by a variety of different methods and this is a welcomed change in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
