<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows 7 on Chris Titus Tech</title>
    <link>/categories/windows-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows 7 on Chris Titus Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 22:53:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/windows-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raid Re-syncing Windows software raid</title>
      <link>/windows-software-raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 22:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-software-raid/</guid>
      <description>I want to preface this article in saying that I would never use a software raid in a business environment. However, recently I tried the windows software raid on a home theater PC. We recently had a power issue and caused the RAID 1 to go into resyncing status. Since it was about 2 TB of data, the resync would take several days and be causing performance issues. I found I could not break the raid or remove the mirror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove or Hide System Reserved Partition</title>
      <link>/hide-system-reserved-partition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 17:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hide-system-reserved-partition/</guid>
      <description>Does your system reserve partition have a drive letter? With these steps, you will Hide System Reserved Partition and no longer see it when browsing your computer.
Here is the fix using Diskpart:
 Load Command Prompt (cmd) Load Diskpart (diskpart) List Disks (list disk) Select Proper Disk (select disk #) List Partitions (list partition) Select Proper Partition (select partition #) List Volumes (list volume) NOTE: Look at Drive letter of system reserved volume Select the volume to hide (select volume #) Remove assigned disk letter (remote letter X)  With this, you should no longer see it, and you will Hide System Reserved Partition for good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take ownership of an entire drive in Windows</title>
      <link>/take-ownership-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 16:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/take-ownership-windows/</guid>
      <description>The commands below will show you how to take ownership of an entire drive. Here is a simple script to accomplish just that.
Option 1: Create a cmd file takeowner.cmd in notepad
Option 2: Type the following or past this in a command line prompt one line at a time
takeown /f %1 /r /d y&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; icacls %1 /grant administrators:F /t
Please Note: This will take a large amount of time on big drives</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Error 1327. Invalid Drive” or “Error 1325 – not a valid short file name” Fix</title>
      <link>/valid-short-file-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 20:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/valid-short-file-name/</guid>
      <description>If you are installing a program and receiving a pop-up message during installation of valid short file name this applies to you. I removed a drive from my computer and had this happen to me.
Steps to Fix “not a valid short file name”   Click Start, and then click Run.
  In the Open box, type regedit, and then click OK.
  Under Registry Editor, locate the following registry key: HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Explorer\Shell Folders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Windows 7 from installing device drivers from Windows Update</title>
      <link>/keep-windows-7-from-installing-device-drivers-from-windows-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 15:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/keep-windows-7-from-installing-device-drivers-from-windows-update/</guid>
      <description>I find a very annoying feature of Windows 7 is every device you install by default searches windows update. This makes installing devices a lot longer than it needs to be. Follow these steps to make windows search your computer first and then Windows Update if needed.
  Right Click My Computer from Start Menu and select “Properties”
  Click “Advanced System Settings”
  Select Hardware Tab, and click “Device Installation Settings”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force Network Connection Priority</title>
      <link>/force-network-connection-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 19:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/force-network-connection-priority/</guid>
      <description>This describes how to have an adapter take priority of all internet traffic over another. For instance, you have 2 different networks on a single computer, and the wired connection does all your internal communications, but you want the wireless adapter to do all outgoing internet applications (iexplore, firefox, etc…).
Set the Interface Metric
 -Open Network Connections (ncpa.cpl)
  -Open the Network Connection to take priority (Right click desired connection -&amp;gt; Properties)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>