<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Chris Titus Tech</title>
    <link>/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Chris Titus Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 16:18:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create iSCSI SR in XenServer</title>
      <link>/create-iscsi-sr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 16:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/create-iscsi-sr/</guid>
      <description>This guide goes over how to Create iSCSI SR on Xen to connect to an iSCSI target. Here is the step-by-step and a video walkthrough, which includes setting up iSCSI in FreeNAS.
Requirements  Multiple XenServers (2+) in a Pool iSCSI target (Check out FreeNAS in the video below for setting one up) At LEAST a gigabit environment   Step-by-Step Guide to Create iSCSI SR  Open and Connect to XenCenter / XCP-ng Center Select Pool and Click New Storage Make sure iSCSI is selected Name Storage Select either provisioning methods Enter IP Address / Authentication (if needed) / Click Scan Target Host Pick IQN / LUN from your storage device  Note: When Selecting IQN_, make sure you select your SAN if you are using a dedicated network_   Finish  Video Walkthrough In the end, we now have a centralized storage system that all our hosts can put their VMs on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Windows Firewall Properly</title>
      <link>/disable-windows-firewall-properly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 17:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/disable-windows-firewall-properly/</guid>
      <description>This walkthrough goes over how to Disable Windows Firewall while not affecting other programs that rely on this service. It’s important that you **DO NOT **disable the service, due to the fact it can cause issues with Microsoft Office and other products.
 Steps to bypass firewall  Launch Windows Defender Firewall with Advanced Security (Start -&amp;gt; Run -&amp;gt; wf.msc) Click Inbound Rules Select “New Rule” Custom rule All Programs Leave Any and All Ports Any IP Address for both Allow the connection Check Domain, Private, and Public Name “Allow All”  Video Guide Finishing Up By doing this you allow all traffic inbound to this computer, consequently, all outbound traffic is already allowed by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and Configuring Exchange 2019</title>
      <link>/configuring-exchange-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 15:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/configuring-exchange-2019/</guid>
      <description>This article goes over what it takes for installing and configuring exchange 2019. This step-by-step guide shows you the requirements, installation steps, and basic configuration.
Requirements  Microsoft recommends 128 GB of memory. If in a medium size environment (100-1000 users) 32-64 GB will be sufficient. Microsoft Windows Server 2012 R2/2016/2019 Co-Existence with Exchange 2013/2016 that are up-to-date 30 GB of free disk space, however, you should have plenty of TBs of storage available for the mailbox stores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XenServer cannot connect in XenCenter or XCP-ng Center</title>
      <link>/xenserver-cannot-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/xenserver-cannot-connect/</guid>
      <description>Having problems and your XenServer cannot connect to XenCenter? Did you have high availability enabled? If you answered yes to both these questions here is how you get your XenServer back online and functioning properly.

Step-by-Step Guide  PuTTy into the XenServer Pool Master run the following commands:  xe pool-ha-disable_Note: If this fails try ha-disable force below_
xe host-emergency-ha-disable force=true&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; xe pool-emergency-transition-to-master --force
Note: This will force the pool and slaves to reinitialize with the pool master</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and Configuring Windows Server 2016 Core</title>
      <link>/configuring-windows-server-2016-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/configuring-windows-server-2016-core/</guid>
      <description>This guide walks you through how to installing and configuring windows server 2016 core, afterward you will easily be able to add one to your environment with very little resources. Start off by using the video guide over the installation process. Once done, check the bullets below to help walk you through doing it in your infrastructure.
Remote Server Administration Tools for Windows 10 https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=45520
 Steps to configuring windows server 2016 core  Run sconfig Configure Static IP Set Computer Name Join to Domain Set Windows Update Settings to Download ONLY Download and Install all Updates Enable Remote Desktop and Remote Management Change Telemetry to Security Activate Windows Reboot  Connecting Remotely to Server 2016 Core Finally, we can now go back to our workstation and start utilizing and configuring windows server 2016 core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Apache Memory Usage using mpm prefork</title>
      <link>/apache-mpm-prefork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 17:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/apache-mpm-prefork/</guid>
      <description>This guide goes over optimizing apache memory usage by configuring mpm prefork module to the best values for your server. Afterword, you should notice substantial increases in performance especially if you are using free micro instances from Google Cloud or AWS.
Commands used:  Check Apache Memory usage   ps -ylC apache2 --sort:rss | awk &#39;{sum+=$8; ++n} END {print &amp;quot;Tot=&amp;quot;sum&amp;quot;(&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;)&amp;quot;;print &amp;quot;Avg=&amp;quot;sum&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;=&amp;quot;sum/n/1024&amp;quot;MB&amp;quot;}&#39;
Note: My result was between 68-71 MB with stock modules loaded, however, your results will vary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commiting Changes to Docker images and containers</title>
      <link>/commiting-docker-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 19:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/commiting-docker-images/</guid>
      <description>This is a walkthrough of how to commit changes to docker images and containers. You need to do this if you make configuration changes to any docker images. By committing changes to the docker images you can backup and clone them.
Docker is a very powerful tool you can use to isolate applications, therefore, you won’t have them on a single server. However, some docker images don’t save changes to their container when a restart happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing file permissions using PowerShell</title>
      <link>/changing-file-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 15:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/changing-file-permissions/</guid>
      <description>Use the following script for changing file permissions using PowerShell. I use this script when command line takeown and icacls fail. Obviously, run from an elevated PowerShell prompt or by typing ‘powershell’ from elevated cmd.
The Script Change $folder to the base directory you want for changing permissions.
Please note, you can use network UNC paths for this or a simple C:.
$folder = &amp;quot;\\homeserver\users\&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; $users = get-childitem $folder&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Foreach ($user in $users) {&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; $acl = Get-Acl $user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Nagios 4 Core Installation</title>
      <link>/troubleshooting-nagios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 17:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/troubleshooting-nagios/</guid>
      <description>Use the following command to verify you have all your config and command files correct when troubleshooting Nagios core installation. This will give you a readout of any configuration errors, thus giving you the ability to fix it on the fly.
/usr/local/nagios/bin/nagios -v /usr/local/nagios/etc/nagios.cfg
I’d recommend making an alias in your .bashrc so you can just type:testnag
Here is an example of the alias I use
alias testnag=&#39;/usr/local/nagios/bin/nagios -v /usr/local/nagios/etc/nagios.cfg&#39;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a startup program to run as administrator</title>
      <link>/run-as-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 02:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/run-as-administrator/</guid>
      <description>The following script shows you how to launch a startup program to run as administrator in Windows 10. This fixes many programs that require elevation and you don’t want to launch manually every time.
Almost every online tutorial I came across said to run it as a scheduled task. This is very cumbersome and I hate it, however using the following method is easier and saves you time.
Create a Text file in shell:startup and put the following in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud migration hosting in Google, Amazon, or Microsoft</title>
      <link>/cloud-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 21:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud-migration/</guid>
      <description>Moving to the Cloud The following article outlines what it takes for a cloud migration to Google Cloud Compute, Amazon Web Services, or Microsoft Azure means. Most businesses want to move to the “cloud” but have no idea what that means. If you’re a small business you typically have a couple computers scattered around with one storage device. If you’re a medium or large business you probably already have several servers at a location in a contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Swap file on Cloud VM (AWS, GCloud, or Azure)</title>
      <link>/create-swap-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 21:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/create-swap-file/</guid>
      <description>Use the commands below to create swap file on a micro instance with a Linux operating system. This creates a 2GB Swap file to help alleviate low system ram. Consequently, this is great for those using micro instances in the cloud that have under 1 GB of memory.
Commands Run the following from your SSH window
sudo fallocate -l 2G /swapfile&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo chmod 600 /swapfile&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo mkswap /swapfile&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo swapon /swapfile&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; sudo swapon -s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force active directory sync to Office 365 with Azure ADSync</title>
      <link>/force-active-directory-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/force-active-directory-sync/</guid>
      <description>Use the following from an Elevated Powershell Prompt to force active directory sync to your O365 admin portal. You will be performing this on the server where Azure AD Sync is installed, however, when running this command you will need to wait 5 minutes before checking your portal to verify it is working. In larger environments, this can take a longer time.
Import-Module “C:\Program Files\Microsoft Azure AD Sync\Bin\ADSync\ADSync.psd1”&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; Start-ADSyncSyncCycle -PolicyType Delta</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Full Access to all Public Folders for a user in Exchange</title>
      <link>/grant-full-access-public-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 16:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/grant-full-access-public-folders/</guid>
      <description>This post goes over how to grant full access to all public folders for a user in Microsoft Exchange. I recently was migrating all public folders from an Exchange 2010 to Office 365 Environment and didn’t have access to some of the folders. Consequently, this solution saved me a lot of time from doing it through a GUI.
Command Enter the following in Exchange Management Shell:
Get-PublicFolder –Identity &amp;quot;\Root Folder Name&amp;quot; -Recurse | Add-PublicFolderAdministrativePermission -User &amp;quot;ctitus&amp;quot; -AccessRights AllExtendedRights</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>