<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exchange Server on Northendlab | Creative Blog Template</title>
    <link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/tags/exchange-server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exchange Server on Northendlab | Creative Blog Template</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 20:29:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/tags/exchange-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exclude shared mailboxes from Dynamic Distribution Group</title>
      <link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/exclude-shared-mailboxes-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 20:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/exclude-shared-mailboxes-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This shows you how to exclude shared mailboxes from a Dynamic Distribution Group in Exchange Online. We will be using Powershell to make sure your shared mailboxes don’t get spam in them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevent autodiscover on Exchange server after an Office 365 Migration</title>
      <link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/prevent-autodiscover-exchange-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 16:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/prevent-autodiscover-exchange-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article teaches you how to prevent autodiscover from happening on Exchange Server. This is important on an Office 365 migration when you still need to keep your local exchange server from resolving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Full Access to all Public Folders for a user in Exchange</title>
      <link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/grant-full-access-public-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 16:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/grant-full-access-public-folders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post goes over how to grant full access to all public folders for a user in Microsoft Exchange. I recently was migrating all public folders from an Exchange 2010 to Office 365 Environment and didn’t have access to some of the folders. Consequently, this solution saved me a lot of time from doing it through a GUI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outlook Security Certificate is invalid</title>
      <link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/outlook-security-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 21:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/outlook-security-certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following article fixes the Outlook security certificate error your users get when they connect to your exchange server internally. This is typically from installing a 3rd party SSL Certificate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving GFI MailArchiver to another server</title>
      <link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/moving-gfi-mailarchiver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 16:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/moving-gfi-mailarchiver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following walkthrough shows you the process of moving GFI MailArchiver to another server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could not continue installation because update is pending</title>
      <link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/update-is-pending/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 19:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/update-is-pending/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When installing a program I kept getting the prompt below that an update is pending. Even after a restart, this would display, therefore I changed these registry keys to clear up the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange on Primary Domain Controller Slow Reboot and Startup</title>
      <link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/exchange-primary-domain-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 20:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/northendlab/exchange-primary-domain-controller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you had the misfortune of installing Exchange on Primary Domain Controller you will experience some pain when doing a reboot. Typically it will take 10-15 minutes before it restarts and up to 30 minutes to start the Microsoft Exchange Information Store. Consequently, what is really happening in the background is the IS service is being terminated incorrectly on shutdown and the store is left in a “DIRTY” shutdown state. This is very bad on several levels and can cause the Store to corrupt and not start at all, which can be catastrophic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
