<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robocopy on Chris Titus Tech | Tech Content Creator</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/robocopy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robocopy on Chris Titus Tech | Tech Content Creator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 17:39:34 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/robocopy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Robocopy - Copying files the right way in Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/robocopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 17:39:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/robocopy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This guide shows how to copy files in windows when dealing with large volumes of files and very long file paths past 255 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-robocopy-and-why-use-it&#34;&gt;What is Robocopy and Why use it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robocopy is a build in command line program that is fantastic at copying files quickly and bypasses many of the downsides of the standard copy process of windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downsides of Window&amp;rsquo;s standard file copy are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has to read ALL files being copied BEFORE it will copy the first file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artificial character limit of 255 that includes the filename and filepath.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GUI limitations for LARGE amounts of files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use-robocopy&#34;&gt;How to use Robocopy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launch into the Command Prompt or Powershell by right-clicking Start Menu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2022/01-Robocopy/start-menu.png&#34; alt=&#34;start-menu&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this interface you can now run Robocopy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic Syntax:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;C:\&amp;gt; robocopy &amp;#34;Source Directory&amp;#34; &amp;#34;Destination Directory&amp;#34; /e /w:5 /r:2 /COPY:DATSOU /DCOPY:DAT /MT
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full syntax can be shown with &lt;code&gt;robocopy /?&lt;/code&gt; but be careful with /MIR and move style copies as this can overwrite and erase existing files in the destination directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable Options with Robocopy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/e - Copy all folders including empty ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/r - Retry times /r:0 means no retry on failed copy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/w - Wait time /w:0 means no wait between retry on failed copy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/COPYALL OR /COPY:DATSOU - Copy Data, Attributes, Timestamps, Security, Owner, and Auditing Info for files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/DCOPY:DAT - Copy Data,Attributes and Timestamps for Directories (Other Options are E=EAs-Extended Attributes, X=Skip alt data streams, but are almost never used)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/MT:n - Multithread transfer with n threads. Example /MT:4 - Use 4 threads to copy files. If no threads set, it will default to 8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/MIR - Mirror Source to Destination - WARNING: WILL DELETE ANY FILES THAT DO NOT MATCH IN DESTINATION!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/MOVE - Moves from Source to Destination - WARNING: WILL DELETE ALL FILES FROM SOURCE AFTER COPY!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/LFSM:100M - Operate in Low Free Space Mode with 100 Megabytes. 10M = 10 Megabytes 1G = 1 Gigabyte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/B - Backup Mode - Great for system backups if you are part of Administrator or Backup Users group - NOT RECOMMENDED - Use 3rd party backup software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ZB - Restartable Backup Mode - Tries to copy files with restartable and if it fails it restarts in backup mode - NOT RECOMMENDED - Use 3rd party backup software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/RH:1700-0900 - Scheduled run between 5PM and 9AM and will pause if it is during &amp;ldquo;business hours of 9AM-5PM&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/LOG+:C:\robocopy.log - Outputs everything to C:\robocopy.log (Note: if NOT running as admin you need to put this in your user folder C:\Users\username\robocopy.log) the + adds to the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/TEE - If using LOG and you also want console output, put the /TEE option in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend using backup, restartable mode, or jobs. Jobs typically miss options and 3rd party solution like veeam are FAR better for backups than robocopy EVER will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;walkthrough-video&#34;&gt;Walkthrough Video&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0q3rGK_IMZg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
